<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Nichtsein</title>
  
  <subtitle>兩岸青山猶在 不見當年故人</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-05-31T10:13:39.904Z</updated>
  <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>崑崙</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>“Go NASA, Go SpaceX, God Bless Bob and Doug”</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/31/%E2%80%9CGo%20NASA,%20Go%20SpaceX,%20God%20Bless%20Bob%20and%20Doug%E2%80%9D/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/31/%E2%80%9CGo%20NASA,%20Go%20SpaceX,%20God%20Bless%20Bob%20and%20Doug%E2%80%9D/</id>
    <published>2020-05-31T03:35:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T10:13:39.904Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/rxNsgDGwjpUd71z.png" alt="img"></p><blockquote><p>The vast ocean of stars can always carry our infinite imagination.</p><p align="right">——劉慈欣</p></blockquote><a id="more"></a><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/yNqVY35GFztJdKg.png" alt="img"></p><p>Elon Musk 這個瘋子開創了人類航天新紀元。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/rxNsgDGwjpUd71z.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vast ocean of stars can always carry our infinite imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;——劉慈欣&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>John F. Kennedy：Presidential Inaugural Address</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/John%20F.%20Kennedy%EF%BC%9APresidential%20Inaugural%20Address/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/John%20F.%20Kennedy%EF%BC%9APresidential%20Inaugural%20Address/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T15:15:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T09:36:45.944Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=753262888&bvid=BV1zk4y167L2&cid=197165599&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>Vice President Johnson, Mr. Speaker, Mr. Chief Justice, President Eisenhower, Vice President Nixon, President Truman, reverend clergy, fellow citizens:</p><p>We observe today not a victory of party, but a celebration of freedom – symbolizing an end,as well as a beginning – signifying renewal, as well as change. For I have sworn before you and Almighty God the same solemn oath our forebears prescribed nearly a century and threequarters ago.</p><p>The world is very different now. For man holds in his mortal hands the power to abolish all forms of human poverty and all forms of human life. And yet the same revolutionary beliefs for which our forebears fought are still at issue around the globe – the belief that the rights of man come not from the generosity of the state, but from the hand of God.</p><p>We dare not forget today that we are the heirs of that first revolution. Let the word go forth from this time and place, to friend and foe alike, that the torch has been passed to a new generation of Americans – born in this century, tempered by war, disciplined by a hard and bitter peace, proud of our ancient heritage, and unwilling to witness or permit the slow undoing of those human rights to which this nation has always been committed, and to which we are committed today at home and around the world.  </p><p>Let every nation know, whether it wishes us well or ill, that we shall pay any price, bear any burden, meet any hardship, support any friend, oppose any foe, to assure the survival and the success of liberty.</p><p>This much we pledge – and more.</p><p>To those old allies whose cultural and spiritual origins we share, we pledge the loyalty of faithful friends. United there is little we cannot do in a host of cooperative ventures. Divided there is little we can do – for we dare not meet a powerful challenge at odds and split asunder.</p><p>To those new states whom we welcome to the ranks of the free, we pledge our word that one form of colonial control shall not have passed away merely to be replaced by a far more iron tyranny. We shall not always expect to find them supporting our view. But we shall always hope to find them strongly supporting their own freedom – and to remember that, in the past, those who foolishly sought power by riding the back of the tiger ended up inside. To those people in the huts and villages of half the globe struggling to break the bonds of mass misery, we pledge our best efforts to help them help themselves, for whatever period is required – not because the Communists may be doing it, not because we seek their votes,but because it is right. If a free society cannot help the many who are poor, it cannot save the few who are rich.</p><p>To our sister republics south of our border, we offer a special pledge: to convert our good words into good deeds, in a new alliance for progress, to assist free men and free governments in casting off the chains of poverty. But this peaceful revolution of hope cannot become the prey of hostile powers. Let all our neighbors know that we shall join with them to oppose aggression or subversion anywhere in the Americas. And let every other power know that this hemisphere intends to remain the master of its own house.</p><p>To that world assembly of sovereign states, the United Nations, our last best hope in an age where the instruments of war have far outpaced the instruments of peace, we renew our pledge of support – to prevent it from becoming merely a forum for invective, to strengthen its shield of the new and the weak, and to enlarge the area in which its writ may run.</p><p>Finally, to those nations who would make themselves our adversary, we offer not a pledge but a request: that both sides begin anew the quest for peace, before the dark powers of destruction unleashed by science engulf all humanity in planned or accidental self-destruction.</p><p>We dare not tempt them with weakness. For only when our arms are sufficient beyond doubt can we be certain beyond doubt that they will never be employed.  </p><p>But neither can two great and powerful groups of nations take comfort from our present course – both sides overburdened by the cost of modern weapons, both rightly alarmed by the steady spread of the deadly atom, yet both racing to alter that uncertain balance of terror that stays the hand of mankind’s final war.</p><p>So let us begin anew – remembering on both sides that civility is not a sign of weakness, and sincerity is always subject to proof. Let us never negotiate out of fear, but let us never fear to negotiate.</p><p>Let both sides explore what problems unite us instead of belaboring those problems which divide us.</p><p>Let both sides, for the first time, formulate serious and precise proposals for the inspection and control of arms, and bring the absolute power to destroy other nations under the absolute control of all nations.</p><p>Let both sides seek to invoke the wonders of science instead of its terrors. Together let us explore the stars, conquer the deserts, eradicate disease, tap the ocean depths, and encourage the arts and commerce.</p><p>Let both sides unite to heed, in all corners of the earth, the command of Isaiah – to “undo the heavy burdens, and [to] let the oppressed go free.”</p><p>And, if a beachhead of cooperation may push back the jungle of suspicion, let both sides join in creating a new endeavor – not a new balance of power, but a new world of law – where the strong are just, and the weak secure, and the peace preserved.</p><p>All this will not be finished in the first one hundred days. Nor will it be finished in the first one thousand days; nor in the life of this Administration; nor even perhaps in our lifetime on this planet. But let us begin.</p><p>In your hands, my fellow citizens, more than mine, will rest the final success or failure of our course. Since this country was founded, each generation of Americans has been summoned to give testimony to its national loyalty. The graves of young Americans who answered the call to service surround the globe.</p><p>Now the trumpet summons us again – not as a call to bear arms, though arms we need – not as a call to battle, though embattled we are – but a call to bear the burden of a long twilight struggle, year in and year out, “rejoicing in hope; patient in tribulation,” a struggle against the common enemies of man: tyranny, poverty, disease, and war itself.</p><p>Can we forge against these enemies a grand and global alliance, North and South, East and West, that can assure a more fruitful life for all mankind? Will you join in that historic effort?</p><p>In the long history of the world, only a few generations have been granted the role of defending freedom in its hour of maximum danger. I do not shrink from this responsibility – I welcome it. I do not believe that any of us would exchange places with any other people or any other generation. The energy, the faith, the devotion which we bring to this endeavor will light our country and all who serve it. And the glow from that fire can truly light the world. </p><p>And so, my fellow Americans, ask not what your country can do for you; ask what you can do for your country.</p><p>My fellow citizens of the world, ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man.</p><p>Finally,whether you are citizens of America or citizens of the world, ask of us here the same high standards of strength and sacrifice which we ask of you. With a good conscience our only sure reward, with history the final judge of our deeds, let us go forth to lead the land we love,asking His blessing and His help, but knowing that here on earth God’s work must truly be our own.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=753262888&amp;bvid=BV1zk4y167L2&amp;cid=197165599&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>千日紀事</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/%E5%8D%83%E6%97%A5%E7%B4%80%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/%E5%8D%83%E6%97%A5%E7%B4%80%E4%BA%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T09:45:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T09:51:48.701Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/aZdrF6ePhMGyv3Y.jpg" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><p>庚子年閏四月初八日。</p><p>晴空萬里</p><p>自2017-09-03到2020-05-30，已然走入大學達千日。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/aZdrF6ePhMGyv3Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>George W. Bush：911 Address to the Nation</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/George%20W.%20Bush%EF%BC%9A911%20Address%20to%20the%20Nation/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/George%20W.%20Bush%EF%BC%9A911%20Address%20to%20the%20Nation/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:50:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:19:00.197Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=838262311&bvid=BV1vg4y1B7bn&cid=196498473&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>Good evening.</p><p>Today, our fellow citizens, our way of life, our very freedom came under attack in a series of deliberate and deadly terrorist acts. The victims were in airplanes or in their offices: secretaries, business men and women, military and federal workers, moms and dads, friends and neighbors. Thousands of lives were suddenly ended by evil, despicable acts of terror. The pictures of airplanes flying into buildings, fires burning, huge ­­ huge structures collapsing have filled us with disbelief, terrible sadness, and a quiet, unyielding anger. These acts of mass murder were intended to frighten our nation into chaos and retreat. But they have failed. Our country is strong.</p><p>A great people has been moved to defend a great nation. Terrorist attacks can shake the foundations of our biggest buildings, but they cannot touch the foundation of America. These acts shatter steel, but they cannot dent the steel of American resolve. America was targeted for attack because we’re the brightest beacon for freedom and opportunity in the world. And no one will keep that light from shining. Today, our nation saw evil ­­ the very worst of human nature ­­ and we responded with the best of America. With the daring of our rescue workers,with the caring for strangers and neighbors who came to give blood and help in any way they could.</p><p>Immediately following the first attack, I implemented our government’s emergency response plans. Our military is powerful, and it’s prepared. Our emergency teams are working in New York City and Washington D.C. to help with local rescue efforts. Our first priority is to get help to those who have been injured, and to take every precaution to protect our citizens at home and around the world from further attacks. The functions of our government continue without interruption. Federal agencies in Washington which had to be evacuated today are reopening for essential personnel tonight and will be open for business tomorrow. Our financial institutions remain strong, and the American economy will be open for business as well.</p><p>The search is underway for those who were behind these evil acts. I have directed the full resources of our intelligence and law enforcement communities to find those responsible andto bring them to justice. We will make no distinction between the terrorists who committedthese acts and those who harbor them.</p><p>Iappreciate so very much the members of Congress who have joined me in strongly condemning these attacks. And on behalf of the American people, I thank the many world leaders who have called to offer their condolences and assistance. America and our friendsand allies join with all those who want peace and security in the world, and we stand togetherto win the war against terrorism.</p><p>Tonight, I ask for your prayers for all those who grieve, for the children whose worlds have been shattered, for all whose sense of safety and security has been threatened. And I pray they will be comforted by a Power greater than any of us, spoken through the ages in Psalm23: Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I fear no evil for you are with me.</p><p>This is a day when all Americans from every walk of life unite in our resolve for justice and peace. America has stood down enemies before, and we will do so this time. None of us will ever forget this day, yet we go forward to defend freedom and all that is good and just in our world.</p><p>Thank you. Good night. And God bless America.  </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=838262311&amp;bvid=BV1vg4y1B7bn&amp;cid=196498473&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Beautiful Mind - The Nobel Prize</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/A%20Beautiful%20Mind%20-%20The%20Nobel%20Prize/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/A%20Beautiful%20Mind%20-%20The%20Nobel%20Prize/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:48:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:39.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=840782239&bvid=BV1q54y1D7qq&cid=196323697&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=840782239&amp;bvid=BV1q54y1D7qq&amp;cid=196323697&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dilios&#39; Battle Call at Plataea</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Dilios&#39;%20Battle%20Call%20at%20Plataea/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Dilios&#39;%20Battle%20Call%20at%20Plataea/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:46:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:21.839Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=243340752&bvid=BV1kv411z7aD&cid=196323093&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=243340752&amp;bvid=BV1kv411z7aD&amp;cid=196323093&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>【梅豔芳】似是故人來</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%A2%85%E8%B1%94%E8%8A%B3%E3%80%91%E4%BC%BC%E6%98%AF%E6%95%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%BE%86/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%A2%85%E8%B1%94%E8%8A%B3%E3%80%91%E4%BC%BC%E6%98%AF%E6%95%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%BE%86/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T03:10:21.446Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:17:37.374Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=285790377&bvid=BV1Pf4y127GQ&cid=196286766&page=1&high_quality=1"  scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><p>深夜配老歌，明月在天。</p><a id="more"></a><p>昨日同可愛夜聊。聊到了許多老歌，如此夜晚，老歌更让人回味。粵語保留了許多中古漢語的音調，聲調豐富，吟唱國語詞最合適不過。</p><p>初聽《似是故人來》，是洪塵的翻唱版，洪塵嗓音乾淨環味。若是要爲自己那段時間做一首音樂註腳，莫過於這首《似是故人來》。林夕作詞，頗有長短句之韻。“恨臺上卿卿，或臺下我我，不是我跟你” 和 “斷腸字點點，風雨聲連連，似是故人來”，最是讓人絞腸。</p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=530 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=2&id=543747557&auto=0&height=66"></iframe><hr><center>作詞：林夕  作曲：羅大佑</center><center>同是過路，同做過夢</center><center>本應是一對</center><center>人在少年，夢中不覺</center><center>醒後要歸去</center><center>三餐一宿，也共一雙</center><center>到底會是誰</center><center>但凡未得到</center><center>但凡是過去</center><center>總是最登對</center><center>臺下你望，臺上我做</center><center>你想做的戲</center><center>前世故人，忘憂的你</center><center>可曾記得起</center><center>歡喜傷悲，老病生死</center><center>說不上傳奇</center><center>恨臺上卿卿</center><center>或臺下我我</center><center>不是我跟你</center><center>俗塵渺渺</center><center>天意茫茫</center><center>將你共我分開</center><center>斷腸字點點</center><center>風雨聲連連</center><center>似是故人來</center><center>何日再追，何地再醉</center><center>說今夜真美</center><center>無份有緣，回憶不斷</center><center>生命卻苦短</center><center>一種相思，兩段苦戀 </center><center>半生說沒完</center><center>在年月深淵</center><center>望明月遠遠</center><center>想像你憂鬱</center><center>俗塵渺渺</center><center>天意茫茫</center><center>將你共我分開</center><center>斷腸字點點</center><center>風雨聲連連</center><center>似是故人來</center><center>留下你或留下我</center><center>在世間上終老</center><center>離別以前</center><center>未知相對當日那麼好</center><center>執子之手</center><center>卻又分手</center><center>愛得有還無</center><center>十年後雙雙</center><center>萬年後對對</center><center>只恨看不到</center><center>十年後雙雙</center><center>萬年後對對</center><center>只恨看不到</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=285790377&amp;bvid=BV1Pf4y127GQ&amp;cid=196286766&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot;  scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;深夜配老歌，明月在天。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Queen Gorgo Address the Spartan Apella</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Queen%20Gorgo%20Address%20the%20Spartan%20Apella/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Queen%20Gorgo%20Address%20the%20Spartan%20Apella/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T01:59:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:17:10.770Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=837832074&bvid=BV1Pg4y1z7HL&cid=196258724&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true"sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>希波戰爭期間，波斯國王薛西斯一世親率30萬大軍征戰希臘，希臘防線最前線便是溫泉關，此處亦是波斯前往希臘的必經之路。叛徒出賣之後，斯巴達國王列奧尼達為保留希臘聯軍實力，讓聯軍先撤退，而自己率三百斯巴達勇士死守溫泉關。</p><p>視頻中，他的女人——斯巴達王后戈爾戈在兩軍交戰明顯己方處於劣勢的背景下，憑藉三寸之舌，以一國王后的傲然氣勢，說服議會出兵抗擊波斯，解救斯巴達勇士。</p><p>有件軼事能一窺戈爾戈的氣魄。有次戈爾戈訪問雅典，一個女人問她，為何斯巴達女人能控制住自己的男人。戈爾戈回答，因為只有斯巴達女人能生男人。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=837832074&amp;bvid=BV1Pg4y1z7HL&amp;cid=196258724&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>【浮生一紀】悲喜交加的故事</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%B5%AE%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%80%E7%B4%80%E3%80%91%E6%82%B2%E5%96%9C%E4%BA%A4%E5%8A%A0%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%B5%AE%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%80%E7%B4%80%E3%80%91%E6%82%B2%E5%96%9C%E4%BA%A4%E5%8A%A0%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T01:00:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:07.812Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710873160&bvid=BV1vQ4y1P7ni&cid=196205833&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true"sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710873160&amp;bvid=BV1vQ4y1P7ni&amp;cid=196205833&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>《共產黨宣言》1872年德文版序言</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/28/%E3%80%8A%E5%85%B1%E7%94%A2%E9%BB%A8%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80%E3%80%8B1872%E5%B9%B4%E5%BE%B7%E6%96%87%E7%89%88%E5%BA%8F%E8%A8%80/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/28/%E3%80%8A%E5%85%B1%E7%94%A2%E9%BB%A8%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80%E3%80%8B1872%E5%B9%B4%E5%BE%B7%E6%96%87%E7%89%88%E5%BA%8F%E8%A8%80/</id>
    <published>2020-05-28T09:57:35.228Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T00:53:07.523Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://tse2-mm.cn.bing.net/th/id/OIP.8ngFOLynf2yDDOdBfVbMXgHaFE?pid=Api&amp;rs=1" alt="查看源图像" style="zoom: 200%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>共產主義者同盟這個在當時條件下自然只能是秘密團體的國際工人組織， 1847年11月在倫敦舉行的代表大會上委託我們兩人起草一個準備公佈的詳細的理論和實踐的黨綱。 結果就產生了這個《宣言》 ， 《宣言》 原稿在二月革命前幾星期送到倫敦付印。 《宣言》 最初用德文出版， 它用這種文字在德國、 英國和美國至少印過12種不同的版本。 第一個英譯本是由海倫•麥克法林女士翻譯的， 於1850年在倫敦《紅色共和黨人》 雜誌上發表， 1871年至少又有三種不同的英譯本在美國出版。 法譯本於1848年六月起義前不久第一次在巴黎印行，最近又有法譯本在紐約《社會主義者報》 上發表；現在有人在準備新譯本。 波蘭文譯本在德文本初版問世後不久就在倫敦出現。 俄譯本是60年代在日內瓦出版的。 丹麥文譯本也是在原書問世後不久就出版了。</p><p>不管最近25年來的情況發生了多大的變化， 這個《宣言》 中所闡述的一般原理整個說來直到現在還是完全正確的。 某些地方本來可以作一些修改。 這些原理的實際運用， 正如《宣言》 中所說的， 隨時隨地都要以當時的歷史條件為轉移， 所以第二章末尾提出的那些革命措施根本沒有特別的意義。 如果是在今天， 這一段在許多方面都會有不同的寫法了。 由於最近25年來大工業有了巨大發展而工人階級的政黨組織也跟著發展起來， 由於首先有了二月革命的實際經驗而後來尤其是有了無產階級第一次掌握政權達兩月之久的巴黎公社的實際經驗， 所以這個綱領現在有些地方已經過時了。 特別是公社已經證明： “工人階級不能簡單地掌握現成的國家機器， 並運用它來達到自己的目的。 ” (見《法蘭西內戰。 國際工人協會總委員會宣言》 德文版第19頁， 那裡對這個思想作了更詳細的闡述。 ） 其次， 很明顯， 對於社會主義文獻所作的批判在今天看來是不完全的， 因為這一批判只包括到1847年為止， 同樣也很明顯， 關於共產黨人對待各種反對黨派的態度的論述(第四章)雖然在原則上今天還是正確的， 但是就其實際運用來說今天畢竟已經過時， 因為政治形勢已經完全改變， 當時所列舉的那些黨派大部分已被歷史的發展徹底掃除了。</p><p>不管最近25年來的情況發生了多大的變化， 這個《宣言》 中所闡述的一般原理整個說來直到現在還是完全正確的。 某些地方本來可以作一些修改。 這些原理的實際運用， 正如《宣言》 中所說的， 隨時隨地都要以當時的歷史條件為轉移， 所以第二章末尾提出的那些革命措施根本沒有特別的意義。 如果是在今天， 這一段在許多方面都會有不同的寫法了。 由於最近25年來大工業有了巨大發展而工人階級的政黨組織也跟著發展起來， 由於首先有了二月革命的實際經驗而後來尤其是有了無產階級第一次掌握政權達兩月之久的巴黎公社的實際經驗， 所以這個綱領現在有些地方已經過時了。 特別是公社已經證明： “工人階級不能簡單地掌握現成的國家機器， 並運用它來達到自己的目的。 ” (見《法蘭西內戰。 國際工人協會總委員會宣言》 德文版第19頁， 那裡對這個思想作了更詳細的闡述。 ） 其次， 很明顯， 對於社會主義文獻所作的批判在今天看來是不完全的， 因為這一批判只包括到1847年為止， 同樣也很明顯， 關於共產黨人對待各種反對黨派的態度的論述(第四章)雖然在原則上今天還是正確的， 但是就其實際運用來說今天畢竟已經過時， 因為政治形勢已經完全改變， 當時所列舉的那些黨派大部分已被歷史的發展徹底掃除了。</p><p>但是《宣言》 是一個歷史檔,我們已沒有權利來加以修改。 下次再版時也許能加上一篇論述1847年到現在這段時期的導言。 這次再版太倉促了， 我們來不及做這件工作。</p><p align="right">卡爾•馬克思 弗里德里希•恩格斯</p><p align="right">1872年6月24日於倫敦</p><p align="right">載於1872年在萊比錫出版的德文版《共產主義宣言》 一書</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://tse2-mm.cn.bing.net/th/id/OIP.8ngFOLynf2yDDOdBfVbMXgHaFE?pid=Api&amp;amp;rs=1&quot; alt=&quot;查看源图像&quot; style=&quot;zoom: 200%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>記一次LOGO設計</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/24/%E8%A8%98%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1LOGO%E8%A8%AD%E8%A8%88/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/24/%E8%A8%98%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1LOGO%E8%A8%AD%E8%A8%88/</id>
    <published>2020-05-24T10:36:03.334Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-28T10:24:55.008Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/28/BTjko2AmdUrbg85.png" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><a id="more"></a><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/24/NcSmuUQgH9eXIRZ.png" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><p>今日，給自己的網站設計了兩個LOGO，圖中有兩個元素。一隻貓頭鷹和德語單詞NICHTSEIN。貓頭鷹作爲的象徵，語出黑格爾的“密涅瓦的貓頭鷹”，以反思爲哲學特性。德語單詞NICHTSEIN由NICHT和SEIN組成，前者表示否定，後者指代存在，合起來的意思是不存在，也即“無”。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/28/BTjko2AmdUrbg85.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; style=&quot;zoom:150%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>滿目盡光</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/03/15/%E6%BB%BF%E7%9B%AE%E7%9B%A1%E5%85%89/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/03/15/%E6%BB%BF%E7%9B%AE%E7%9B%A1%E5%85%89/</id>
    <published>2020-03-15T08:11:01.654Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-15T08:09:58.982Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ae01.alicdn.com/kf/Ucaf3807ef37a43a7b3a5d9b1797980467.jpg" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><center>今日被這歌詞的旋律所繞樑。</center><center>Baby you’re my ONE and ONLY.</center><center>滿目星辰</center><center>明眸為月</center><center>縱使繁星點點在天</center><center>不若一雙明眸在前</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ae01.alicdn.com/kf/Ucaf3807ef37a43a7b3a5d9b1797980467.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sonnet 1</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/23/Sonnet%201/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/23/Sonnet%201/</id>
    <published>2020-02-23T15:25:43.606Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T15:27:19.879Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/3643290/pexels-photo-3643290.jpeg?auto=compress&cs=tinysrgb&h=750&w=1260" alt="cemetery"></p><a id="more"></a><center>From fairest creatures we desire increase</center><center>That thereby the beauty’s rose might never die</center><center>But as the riper should by time decrease</center><center>His tender heir might bear his memory</center><center>But thou, contracted to thine own bright eyes</center><center>Feed’st thy light’s flame with self-substantial fuel</center><center>Making famine where abundance lies</center><center>Thyself thy foe, to thy sweet self too cruel</center><center>Thou that art now the world’s fresh ornament</center><center>And only herald to the gaudy spring</center><center>Within thine own bud buriest thy content</center><center>And, tender churl, mak’st waste in niggarding</center><center>Pity the world, or else this glutton be</center><center>To  eat the world’s due,  by grave and thee</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.pexels.com/photos/3643290/pexels-photo-3643290.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;h=750&amp;w=1260&quot; alt=&quot;cemetery&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sonnet 73</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/22/Sonnet%2073/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/22/Sonnet%2073/</id>
    <published>2020-02-22T11:04:23.531Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T16:02:02.048Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.freeimageslive.co.uk/image/view/10960/_original" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><center>That time of year thou mayst in me behold</center><center>When yelloe leaves, or none, or few, do hang</center><center>Upon those boughs which shake against the cold</center><center>Bare ruined choirs, where late the sweet birds sang</center><center>In me thou seest the twilight of such day</center><center>As after sunset fadeth in the west</center><center>Which by and by black night doth take away</center><center>Death’s second self, that seals up all in rest</center><center>In me thou seest the glowing of such fire</center><center>That on the ashes of his youth doth lie</center><center>And the Death-bed whereon it must expire</center><center>Consumed with that which it was nourished by</center><center>This thou perceiv’st, which makes thy love more strong</center><center>To love that well, which thou must leave ere long</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.freeimageslive.co.uk/image/view/10960/_original&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sonnet 18</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/21/Sonnet%2018/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/21/Sonnet%2018/</id>
    <published>2020-02-21T12:50:40.574Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-21T12:50:18.932Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1570939276551-59a90ac1b80d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&w=1000&q=80" alt="Shakespeare and Company building during daytime"></p><a id="more"></a><center>Shall I compare thee to a summer’s day?</center><center>Thou art more lovely and more temperate:</center><center>Rough winds do shake the darling buds of May,</center><center>And summer’s lease hath all to short a date;</center><center>Sometime too hot the eye of heaven shines,</center><center>And often is his gold complexion dimmed;</center><center>And every fair from fair sometime declines,</center><center>By chance or nature’s changing course untrimmed:</center><center>But thy eternal summer shall not fade,</center><center>Nor lose possession of that fair thou ow’st,</center><center>Nor shall Death brag thou wand’rest in his shade,</center><center>When in eternal lines to time thou grow’st.</center><center>So long as men can breathe or eyes can see,</center><center>So long lives this, and this gives life to thee.</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1570939276551-59a90ac1b80d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;Shakespeare and Company building during daytime&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Fight Against Injustice</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/14/The%20Fight%20Against%20Injustice/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/14/The%20Fight%20Against%20Injustice/</id>
    <published>2020-02-13T16:01:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-15T15:28:14.167Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img.srgcdn.com/e/cVZoblh4ZkgxRzFWOGxUYW53alYuanBn.jpg" alt="查看源图像"></p><a id="more"></a><p>God, I’m full of so much gratitude right now. And I do not feel elevated above any of my fellow nominees or anyone in this room because we share the same love, the love of film. And this form of expression has given me the most extraordinary life. I don’t know what I’d be without it. But I think the greatest gift that it’s given me, and many of us in this room, is <strong>the opportunity to use our voice for the voiceless.</strong></p><p>I’ve been thinking a lot about some of the distressing issues that we are facing collectively. I think at times we feel, or we’re made to feel, that we champion different causes. But for me, I see commonality. I think, whether we’re talking about gender inequality or racism or queer rights or indigenous rights or animal rights, we’re talking about the fight against injustice. <strong>We’re talking about the fight against the belief that one nation, one people, one race, one gender or one species has the right to dominate, control and use and exploit another with impunity.</strong></p><p><img src="https://cdn.extra.ie/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/10074841/PRI136258495.jpg" alt="查看源图像"></p><p>I think that we’ve become very disconnected from the natural world, and many of us, what we’re guilty of is an egocentric world view — the belief that we’re the center of the universe. We go into the natural world, and we plunder it for its resources. We feel entitled to artificially inseminate a cow, and when she gives birth, we steal her baby, even though her cries of anguish are unmistakable. Then we take her milk that’s intended for her calf, and we put it in our coffee and our cereal. And I think we fear the idea of personal change because we think that we have to sacrifice something, to give something up, but human beings, at our best, are so inventive and creative and ingenious. And I think that when we use love and compassion as our guiding principles, we can create, develop and implement systems of change that are beneficial to all sentient beings and to the environment.</p><p>Now, I have been, I have been a scoundrel in my life. I’ve been selfish. I’ve been cruel at times, hard to work with, and I’m grateful that so many of you in this room have given me a second chance. <strong>And I think that’s when we’re at our best, when we support each other, not when we cancel each other out for past mistakes, but when we help each other to grow, when we educate each other, when we guide each other toward redemption. That is the best of humanity.</strong></p><p>When he was 17, my brother wrote this lyric. He said, “<strong>Run to the rescue with love, and peace will follow.</strong>”</p><hr><p><img src="http://cdn.collider.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/joaquin-phoenix-joker.jpg" alt="查看源图像"></p><p>演講者：<strong>Joaquin Phoenix</strong><br>譯    者：<strong>崑崙</strong></p><p>神吶，此刻我充滿著感激之情。我不認為在下比任一被提名者或在座各位來得高貴，因為我們同享一愛，對電影的愛。電影這一表達方式給了在下不一樣的人生。難以想象若無電影，我會如何。然於我所思，電影給予在下和在座各位最重要的禮物是——以吾之聲，代默者言。</p><p>鄙人已然思考著許多我們共同面臨的令人擔憂的事。思考我們注意到，或我們不得不注意，我們捍衛多樣的信仰。然於在下，吾所見者，共性也。吾思，不論我們談論性別平等、種族主義、同性戀權利、本土主義、動物權利，我們所言者，是謂與不公之鬥爭。我們所言者，乃與一國家、一個人、一種族、一性別、一物種擁有統治、管控、利用和剝削他者的權利而免於懲罰的觀念作鬥爭。</p><p>吾思，我們同此自然世界已然愈漸相隔，於多數人而言，所羞愧者乃自我中心的世界觀——人類是宇宙的中心。人類侵入自然，掠出資源。人類身懷給母牛人工授精之能，然當它一朝分娩，我們竊走它的孩兒，儘管清楚地望見它落下悲痛欲絕之淚。我們使用本該是餵養其幼仔的奶汁，倒入我們的咖啡和穀物食品。吾思，我們惶恐關乎個人轉變的觀念，因我們認為我們不得不為此做出一些犧牲、放棄一些事情，但我們人類，盡之天力，是如此富有創意、善於創造和足智多謀。吾思，當我們以愛和熱情作為導向原則，我們可以創造、發展和實行利於所有可感知生物和環境的轉變體系。</p><p>現在，我曾是，在人生中我曾是一個惡棍，也曾自私自利，有時冷酷粗暴，難以一同工作，在下十分感激在座各位予我第二次機會。吾思，當我們盡之全力，當我們相互支持，而非因過往錯誤而擯棄彼此，當我們助力彼此同進步，當我們互力為師，當我們互引彼此向救贖。此乃至上人性也。</p><p>當我哥哥17歲時，他著下此詩：“懷愛奔向救贖，安寧尾隨而來。”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.srgcdn.com/e/cVZoblh4ZkgxRzFWOGxUYW53alYuanBn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;查看源图像&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>成都七中演講</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/11/%E6%88%90%E9%83%BD%E4%B8%83%E4%B8%AD%E6%BC%94%E8%AC%9B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/11/%E6%88%90%E9%83%BD%E4%B8%83%E4%B8%AD%E6%BC%94%E8%AC%9B/</id>
    <published>2020-02-11T14:29:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-12T14:38:38.784Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>林蔭校區的同學們，高新校區的同學們，網校的同學們：</p><p>你們好！</p><p>在這個非常時期，我很榮幸能代表我們語文備課組，和大家重聚在這個特殊的課堂裡。今天，我們以連線代替了會面、螢幕代替了黑板，雖然形式簡陋，但是我們為高三同學助力的熱情不変。</p><a id="more"></a><p>已經立春了，但今年的冬天卻似乎長得沒有盡頭。新冠肺炎還在肆虐，不知還有多少人正面臨著生離死別，還有多少家庭從此沒有明天。“時代的一粒灰，落在個人頭上，就是一座山。”對現在還掙扎在痛苦中的人們，談生活太奢侈了，有些時候，光是活著，就已經拼盡全力。</p><p>所以我們需要對眼前的苦難哀悼，感同身受地深深地哀悼。現在是未來的過去，我們對眼前的苦難哀悼是為了銘記。多年以後，春天來了又去，當陽光鋪灑在草地，當我們自由地呼吸空氣，當我們開心的歡聚，我們必須記得起若干年前，雪曾落在這片土地。死亡，是一個人的悲劇，遺忘是一個民族的悲劇。</p><p>我們還需要懺悔，因為真正的哀悼開始於懺悔。我們應當懺悔， 明明索爾仁尼琴的警告振聾發聵，我們卻裝聾作啞、卻隨波逐流， 甚至推波助瀾。最終，沒有人能夠置身事外。</p><p>魯迅先生曾經說過，墨寫的謊言掩蓋不住血寫的事實。“有的人，為了守住不會帶到棺材裡去的利益與權柄，在他們還活著的時候， 就因為貪婪而吞食了自己的心肝。當他們開始習慣性撒謊的時候， 也在將自己的親友與同胞推向深淵”。歷史不會因為無視而消失，責任也不能因為回避而逃脫。加繆在《鼠疫》中寫道:“這一切裡面並不存在英雄主義，這只是誠實的問題。與鼠疫鬥爭的唯一方式，只能是誠實。“</p><p>李文亮醫生走了，“我們憤怒於你的預警被當成謠言，我們傷慟於你的死亡竟不是謠言”。說真話的人，我們應該為他們豎碑，要有名有姓，拒絕一切匿名的紀念。</p><p>苦難必將過去，但我們不能把喪事當成喜事，不能把質疑換成讚歌，不能把追責偷換為免職。不能把冬天唱成春的開始，有些人已經埋在了冬天。</p><p>苦難必將過去，但僅止於哀悼和懺悔是不夠的，我們必須反省。</p><p>災難面前，最容易看清人性；一場瘟疫，撕下了誰出將入相的遮羞布？又有哪些媚骨在嘩眾取寵中撿拾著人血饅頭？</p><p>如何讓我們的孩子不成為這樣的人？如何能在下次災難來臨的時候，有更多的口罩，有更少的恐慌，有更多的擔當，有更少的推諉。</p><p>災難面前，也最容易看到人類內心深處的光芒。</p><p>哪些骨頭在風中挺立成了傲岸？哪些天使逆行走向了疫情最前線？哪些普通人的善良讓我們熱淚盈眶？哪些陌生人的溫暖讓我們重燃希望？</p><p>這些無懼無畏，這些不屈不撓，這些點點滴滴，讓我們看到了支撐這個民族歷盡滄桑，飽受磨難，依然屹立不倒的那根脊樑。</p><p>我們避免不了災難，我們卻能做好自己，我們預知不了未來，我們卻清晰的知道，未來在孩子們的手裡。</p><p>今天的這些數字，這些故事，這些人物，這些精神，這些教訓，這些反思，不能只出現在多年以後的課本裡，成為僵硬的答題要點。</p><p>這些真實的一切，應該讓孩子們知道。一張安靜的書桌來之不易，不能只安放沒有思想的大腦。</p><p>我們不是局外人，現在不是，未來更不是。因為，“無窮的遠方，無數的人們，都和我有關。”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;林蔭校區的同學們，高新校區的同學們，網校的同學們：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你們好！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在這個非常時期，我很榮幸能代表我們語文備課組，和大家重聚在這個特殊的課堂裡。今天，我們以連線代替了會面、螢幕代替了黑板，雖然形式簡陋，但是我們為高三同學助力的熱情不変。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>筆桿子和槍桿子</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/11/%E7%AD%86%E6%A1%BF%E5%AD%90%E5%92%8C%E6%A7%8D%E6%A1%BF%E5%AD%90/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/11/%E7%AD%86%E6%A1%BF%E5%AD%90%E5%92%8C%E6%A7%8D%E6%A1%BF%E5%AD%90/</id>
    <published>2020-02-11T13:54:51.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-14T10:22:47.856Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/14001337/Stalin-writing.jpg" alt="img"></p><p>槍桿子以筆桿子為先鋒，古往今來的沙場點兵無不是在提筆成行、落筆成列中展開的。</p><a id="more"></a><hr><p>著者：<strong>Daniel Kalder</strong><br>譯者：<strong>崑崙</strong></p><p>獨裁者，誠然，乃惡人也。同時亦是糟糕的作者。然許多獨夫卻沉浸於身懷極佳文學天賦的幻象中。《我的奮鬥》和毛的語錄（亦稱《紅寶書》）是獨夫作集眾所周知的作品，但他們僅僅是龐大且如煉獄般的圖書館中的冰山一角。此類書籍並非個例：從列寧的《俄國資本主義的發展》到霍梅尼的《伊斯蘭政府》，再到卡扎菲的《綠皮書》，不勝枚舉。</p><p>在20世紀暴政的全盛時期，獨夫的作品被放置於其個人崇拜體系的核心，由官方奉為神聖文本，施加於受制的觀眾。此類書籍往往不忍卒讀，然當其作者掌控著出版系統和教育體系時，可以拘禁和處決那些膽敢作出負面評價的人。</p><p><img src="https://i2.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/14001010/B9GHAW-1024x886.jpg?resize=1023%2C885&ssl=1" alt="img"></p><p>然而，當政權垮臺，這些書籍以極快的速度消失殆盡。那些在獨夫統治之下飽受苦難的人們想要繼續前行，未受苦難的人們則受擾於凋敝的經濟、屍山骸海及其不斷披露出的駭人的文章。 或許正是因此，我不認為將這些書籍掃除出記憶是一個好主意。今天，一代人已發展到忘記冷戰，且對於意識形態和簡化在上世紀所導致的大屠殺知之甚少的地步，但他們逐漸在媒體、學術、出版和政治領域中佔據了重要影響的位置。</p><p>受此驚醒，約八年前我開始閱讀這些獨夫的作品，如Harold Bloom於20世紀90年代對西方正典所做的工作，我按此法來處理這些作品。他們寫了什麼？他們是自行完成了這些著作嗎？他們所做的共性何在？我想要回答這些問題。</p><p>…</p><p>許多人設想，如好萊塢名流，獨夫並未寫作此享受他們聲名的作品。然雖常常如此（列昂尼德·勃列日涅夫幾乎不會花費精力去讀書，遑論寫作）但這卻不是一條普遍的規律。</p><p>於事實而言，20世紀的獨夫們在成為政治領袖之前往往是作家，在紙上書下意識形態想象的預演，待未來手掌千民萬衆以待操練。回顧20世紀初，列寧和墨索里尼在手掌大權之前，均有廿年出版作品的經歷；無獨有偶，鲁霍拉·霍梅尼在成為伊朗至上領袖之前關於伊斯蘭法學和神學寫就長篇大論。但是獨夫們掌權後亦執筆寫作。例如：列寧、史大林、佛朗哥、薩達姆侯賽因、薩拉查、卡扎菲和毛，均無暇於繁忙事務而抽空寫作。</p><p>其作品涵蓋的種類驚人。有如下小說：墨索里尼寫了《紅衣主教的情婦》（<em>The Cardinal’s Mistress</em>），一部難以捧讀的歷史小說；佛朗哥寫《種族》（<em>Raza</em>） 一部內戰的虛構題材小說；薩達姆侯賽因在其執政的最後幾年寫作四部小說，其中包括歷史傳奇《札碧琶與國王》（<em>Zabiba and the King</em>）。卡扎菲寫了不少微型散文；毛、薩拉查、史達林和胡志明均涉獵詩歌；史達林著寫一部語言學小冊子；恩維爾霍查，阿爾巴尼亞之獨夫，寫就了同其對手普魯斯特相比肩的一系列回憶錄，金正日發表了一系列關於歌劇、新聞和電影領域的專題著作，電影領域包括洞察力十足的觀點，例如“電影之畫面必須置於熒幕方顯好看”。</p><p>這些著作當中的絕大多數均為糟糠，但卻頗有一番味道。品讀足夠多的獨夫作品，你便能覺察出這些作者的個人氣質：狂躁睿智之列寧、志堅味乏之史達林、自大傲慢之墨索里尼、極盡枯燥之經濟學家之獨夫 薩拉查…還有薩達姆侯賽因，於《札碧琶與國王》中寫作了領導力、孤獨、強姦和獸姦：</p><blockquote><p>即使是一個動物也滿足一個男人的需求，如果它想和他性交。當一隻母熊擄走一個牧羊人進入伊拉克北部的山巒中，難道不是在試圖取悅他嗎？母熊擄牧羊人進入她的洞穴，看牧羊人，不會遵從她的需求同其性交嗎？難道她不會從樹上或灌木叢中收集堅果來給予牧羊人嗎？難道她不會攀爬上農人的屋檐而竊取奶酪、堅果、甚至是葡萄乾，來予餵牧羊人，以激起牧羊人佔有她的渴望嗎？</p></blockquote><p><img src="https://i0.wp.com/d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/14001536/Zabibah_and_the_King_-_original_cover.jpg?resize=220%2C314&ssl=1" alt="img"></p><p>這些作品的核心是共產主義獨夫所製造出多如星辰的冗詞，此類獨夫誕生於“不出版則消弭”的社會主義傳統，其在於革命領袖藉助生產“理論”產品來生產權威。列寧手掌大權時已然擁有了現成的作品集——他作品全集的第一版於1920年出版，而此時俄國內戰如火如荼地展開。</p><p>當列寧往生，史達林迅速將自身生產為陵墓中木乃伊的卓越詮釋者。在蘇聯的第一衛星國蒙古，獨夫喬巴山安排翻譯列寧和史達林的著作，即使其他的黨員不會閱讀。史達林橫跨中東歐的封疆大吏使用出版的演說集和論文集，其中引用了馬克思、恩格斯、列寧和史達林的話，來確證他們的意識形態箴言，亦如今日之批判理論家引用那一撮預見能力堪憂的權威。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://d24fkeqntp1r7r.cloudfront.net/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/14001337/Stalin-writing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;槍桿子以筆桿子為先鋒，古往今來的沙場點兵無不是在提筆成行、落筆成列中展開的。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>庚子元宵雜談</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/08/%E5%85%83%E5%AE%B5%E9%9B%9C%E8%AB%87/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/08/%E5%85%83%E5%AE%B5%E9%9B%9C%E8%AB%87/</id>
    <published>2020-02-08T15:44:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-14T10:11:25.001Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>今日為宵佳節，屬庚子年春節年末。過了這一天，國人所深受煎熬的庚子春節也就存在於記憶中了。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;p&gt;今日為宵佳節，屬庚子年春節年末。過了這一天，國人所深受煎熬的庚子春節也就存在於記憶中了。&lt;/p&gt;

      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>李公祭</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/07/%E6%9D%8E%E5%85%AC%E7%A5%AD/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/07/%E6%9D%8E%E5%85%AC%E7%A5%AD/</id>
    <published>2020-02-07T05:01:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-14T09:03:35.669Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ae01.alicdn.com/kf/U2c50748061d442ae9fd3b6a0b79c0a6ek.jpg" alt="img"></p><p>公乃吹哨人，記以祭之。</p><a id="more"></a><p>李公文亮，武漢醫者。國朝三六載，生遼東錦州。</p><p>及長，入武大習醫。業成，懸壺武昌。</p><p>己亥歲尾，鄂省病作。其疾也，病毒入體，或溫熱，或咳嗽。狀若昔年非典。公告同窗，警之。</p><p>然斯時天下州府，罕不以穩平自雄。故事，荒災禍病，大而化之，齊民不得與聞。長吏顏：吾城無疾。言疾者必謠。</p><p>緹騎訊公，警之告之，訓之誡之。言之未盡，付之案膜。期期以為天下問題，解決提問之人遂平焉。然計數歷朝，紙未能包火，人無力藏疾。越旬日，疫大作，病者眾，方知公有扁鵲之明，咸謂之吹哨人也。</p><p>公習眼科，疫初，為患者診目，竟染疾。不逾月，歿。享年三十又四。嗚呼，公既也，哀哀父母，衣食何方？嬌嬌妻兒，托寄誰人？每念及此，悲不自禁。</p><p>噫，吾嘗聞為眾人抱薪者，不可使其凍斃於途。然則蒼天悠悠，殲我良人，天亦病哉？天亦毒哉？向使武昌府少得明白之士，哀生眾而憐之，聞公言而警之，寧有天下洶洶而武昌倒懸耶？誠如是，公將不死，無辜亦將不死。</p><p>然國朝之弊，首在吏治。陟罰臧否，仰給上峰。上峰屬穩，則下走者粉飾以迎。火熾刀淩，猶脅肩巧笑：平安哉，盛世哉。乃知楚宮腰肢，寧是戲說。</p><p>秦中鹿馬，另具師承。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ae01.alicdn.com/kf/U2c50748061d442ae9fd3b6a0b79c0a6ek.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;公乃吹哨人，記以祭之。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
