<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Nichtsein</title>
  
  <subtitle>兩岸青山猶在 不見當年故人</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-01T16:27:16.036Z</updated>
  <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>崑崙</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>淺談“現實的個人”</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/02/%E6%B7%BA%E8%AB%87%E2%80%9C%E7%8F%BE%E5%AF%A6%E7%9A%84%E5%80%8B%E4%BA%BA%E2%80%9D/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/02/%E6%B7%BA%E8%AB%87%E2%80%9C%E7%8F%BE%E5%AF%A6%E7%9A%84%E5%80%8B%E4%BA%BA%E2%80%9D/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T16:19:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-01T16:27:16.036Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.tnm.jp/uploads/fckeditor/exhibition/special/2012/kokyu/uid000071_201112141943542854ed86.jpg" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>就費爾巴哈哲學而言，確立起感性確定性，以感性確定性的方式切入現實。不同于以黑格爾哲學為代表的唯心主義，將人做抽象化處理，以頭腦思辨的方式去理解和解釋世界，這時的人是思想體系中的人。費爾巴哈重新拾起唯物主義原則，將主詞切換到具體和現實的存在，觀念從屬於賓詞。費爾巴哈對此前的哲學立場做了顛倒處理。但是費爾巴哈是在感性直觀的基礎上建立起感性確定性，如此一來，費爾巴哈僅是看到存在本身所呈現出來的面目，他沒有能夠從過程本身來理解存在，而僅僅是過程終結是的面目來切入去解釋存在。即費爾巴哈沒有能夠對人的活動和存在本身做成物件性活動，未能建立其以否定性為原則的辯證法視角。而馬克思對費的更新在於，一方面，馬克思繼承了費爾巴哈關於唯物主義的思路和線索，另一方面，馬克思揚棄的費爾巴哈的感性直觀，同時引入了辯證法的否定性作用，把人的活動和存在展開為物件性活動，做成是一個具體的、現實的過程。</p><p>馬克思在《德意志意識形態批判》中談到“人的現實性”：“他們的活動和他們的物質生活條件，包括他們已有的和由他們自己的活動創造出來的物質生活條件。”馬克思從兩個因素來談論人的現實性，一方面是具體的現實的人，這是作為實際存在的個人，而非是思辨思想中的個人，另一方面，是人的物質生產生活條件，這是作為現實存在的個人的存在前提。馬克思還提到：“全部人類歷史的第一個前提無疑是有生命的個人的存在。”人的物理性存在無疑是關於人的一切的前提。“人們用以生產自己的生活資料的方式， 首先取決於他們已有的和需要再生產的生活資料本身的特性。 這種生產方式不應當只從它是個人肉體存在的再生產這方面加以考察， 更確切地說， 它是這些個人的一定的活動方式， 是他們表現自己生命的一定方式、 他們的一定的生活方式。”人掌握、使用生存資料的過程就是人的活動過程，人在現實的、已被創造出的物質條件上進行再生存創造，人的生存、條件、過程和結果都是呈現出實實在在的現實性。因此，是人的創造和生產“生產”出了人的歷史。</p><p>馬克思哲學在關於“現實的人”的解讀中，筆者認為馬克思十分強調人的現實的物質性生產和再創造，以一個過程及其後續性影響的視角來看待歷史本身。一方面他批判了唯心主義的抽象的個人，確立起人的現實性。但另一方面，馬克思對待人類這樣一個有別於其他動物，能自覺生產勞動的生物的視角上，筆者認為，馬克思更關注人的生物性和物理性表現，即人活生生地表現出來的現實的物理活動，但人就存在及其活動，思想性存在也同樣是現實的存在。它體現于人自我勞動時的對其勞動本身的頭腦刻畫。也即，理論和現實的一致性，人的物質生產過程就是其思想生產過程，而非現實之後的反思性加工思考才可稱之為思想。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.tnm.jp/uploads/fckeditor/exhibition/special/2012/kokyu/uid000071_201112141943542854ed86.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; style=&quot;zoom:150%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>庚子閏四月初十日記</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E9%96%8F%E5%9B%9B%E6%9C%88%E5%88%9D%E5%8D%81%E6%97%A5%E8%A8%98/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E9%96%8F%E5%9B%9B%E6%9C%88%E5%88%9D%E5%8D%81%E6%97%A5%E8%A8%98/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T13:54:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-02T01:46:02.871Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://image2.135editor.com/cache/remote/aHR0cHM6Ly9tbWJpei5xbG9nby5jbi9tbWJpei9vSWpzVmljT2VxYUcxc1lFdnNNRmZsdkRVaWNqeFpHYmgxazBhd0QxVmtNajFrRnJiNGFtRld4V2I3VzRXTE9RTkJmYUV0YkdjMGVPdVljSVJqaWM3TTFPdy8w" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>今日，晴，炎熱。</p><p>午後收到一位朋友發來的好消息，他博士面試通過了。實際上這是第二次考核，第一次因爲意外狀況，沒能成功。也因此受到冷言諷語，在去年將近一年的時間裏，整個人都處於十分焦慮的狀態。仍記得回顧上學期期末，和他兩人夜遊校園。當時兩個人狀態相仿，那一次夜遊頗有感傷之情。仍記得，那時他說若是博士面試通過，他便將其詩集出版。當時我還開玩笑：“好，到時候我來寫序言。”那朗朗笑聲縈繞耳邊。</p><p>外部框架下的個人被牢牢鉗制，主客體已然顛倒，或多或少地程序式前進。被大浪潮裹挾著的各個個體作出非自由的決定。</p><p>有人星夜趕科場，有人辭官歸故里。仕途如此，學歷亦如此。另一位朋友，考研複試面試未去，現計劃北漂兼陪女友。在市民社會下，人與人之間的特殊性盡情顯露，爲達到普遍性，八仙過海，各顯神通，手段盡顯。</p><p>不論如何，都要善於在各自的道路限制自己，正是“衣帶漸寬終不悔，爲伊消得人憔悴”。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://image2.135editor.com/cache/remote/aHR0cHM6Ly9tbWJpei5xbG9nby5jbi9tbWJpei9vSWpzVmljT2VxYUcxc1lFdnNNRmZsdkRVaWNqeFpHYmgxazBhd0QxVmtNajFrRnJiNGFtRld4V2I3VzRXTE9RTkJmYUV0YkdjMGVPdVljSVJqaWM3TTFPdy8w&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; style=&quot;zoom:150%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Foever Young</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/Foever%20Young/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/Foever%20Young/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T13:37:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-01T15:02:27.323Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/914HddyUgwL.jpg" alt="img"></p><center>May you always be forever young.</center><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>今日是兒童節，首先來欣賞三首與兒童有關的詩詞。感受一下古人筆下孩童的天真無邪與青春美好。</p><p>&emsp;</p><center>池上二絕·其二</center><center>白居易</center>&emsp;<center>小娃撐小艇，</center><center>偷採白蓮回。</center><center>不解藏蹤跡，</center><center>浮萍一道開。</center><p>&emsp;<br>&emsp;</p><center>清平樂·檢校山園林書所見</center><center>辛棄疾</center>&emsp;<center>連雲松竹，</center><center>萬事從今足。</center><center>拄杖東家分社肉，</center><center>白酒床頭初熟。</center><center>西風梨棗山園，</center><center>兒童偷把長竿。</center><center>莫遣旁人驚去，</center><center>老夫靜處閒看。</center><p>&emsp;<br>&emsp;</p><center>村居</center><center>高鼎</center>&emsp;<center>草長鶯飛二月天，</center><center>拂堤楊柳醉春煙。</center><center>兒童散學歸來早，</center><center>忙趁東風放紙鳶。</center><p>&emsp;</p><p>&emsp;</p><hr><p>&emsp;</p><p>接下來欣賞音樂。第一位是意外在網易雲音樂上發現的博主，初次聽到折服於其聲線，溫柔甜美。後來感受到的是她對於美國民謠的喜歡，做了上百期播客，在她身上不難看到那種對音樂的純粹興趣。</p><p>這首歌是Bob Dylan 的 <em>Forever Young</em> ，正是應和今日主題。</p><p>&emsp;</p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=460 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=3&id=2067410056&auto=0&height=66"></iframe>&emsp;<p>&emsp;</p><p>第二首是縱貫線的《童年》，來自2010年的演唱會。</p><p>&emsp;</p><iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=625912689&bvid=BV15t4y1y7hh&cid=197589280&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/914HddyUgwL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;May you always be forever young.&lt;/center&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>“Go NASA, Go SpaceX, God Bless Bob and Doug”</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/31/%E2%80%9CGo%20NASA,%20Go%20SpaceX,%20God%20Bless%20Bob%20and%20Doug%E2%80%9D/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/31/%E2%80%9CGo%20NASA,%20Go%20SpaceX,%20God%20Bless%20Bob%20and%20Doug%E2%80%9D/</id>
    <published>2020-05-31T03:35:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T14:24:47.400Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/rxNsgDGwjpUd71z.png" alt="img"></p><blockquote><p>Open your eyes, look up to the skies.</p><p align="right">——Elon Musk</p></blockquote><a id="more"></a><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/SvjHpwXYIqQZnl9.png" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/yNqVY35GFztJdKg.png" alt="img"></p><p>Elon Musk 這個瘋子開創了人類航天新紀元。</p><p><img src="http://www.collectspace.com/images/news-052820c.jpg" alt="img"></p><p><img src="http://www.collectspace.com/images/news-052820e.jpg" alt="img"></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/rxNsgDGwjpUd71z.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your eyes, look up to the skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;——Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>John F. Kennedy：Presidential Inaugural Address</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/John%20F.%20Kennedy%EF%BC%9APresidential%20Inaugural%20Address/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/John%20F.%20Kennedy%EF%BC%9APresidential%20Inaugural%20Address/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T15:15:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T09:36:45.944Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=753262888&bvid=BV1zk4y167L2&cid=197165599&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>Vice President Johnson, Mr. Speaker, Mr. Chief Justice, President Eisenhower, Vice President Nixon, President Truman, reverend clergy, fellow citizens:</p><p>We observe today not a victory of party, but a celebration of freedom – symbolizing an end,as well as a beginning – signifying renewal, as well as change. For I have sworn before you and Almighty God the same solemn oath our forebears prescribed nearly a century and threequarters ago.</p><p>The world is very different now. For man holds in his mortal hands the power to abolish all forms of human poverty and all forms of human life. And yet the same revolutionary beliefs for which our forebears fought are still at issue around the globe – the belief that the rights of man come not from the generosity of the state, but from the hand of God.</p><p>We dare not forget today that we are the heirs of that first revolution. Let the word go forth from this time and place, to friend and foe alike, that the torch has been passed to a new generation of Americans – born in this century, tempered by war, disciplined by a hard and bitter peace, proud of our ancient heritage, and unwilling to witness or permit the slow undoing of those human rights to which this nation has always been committed, and to which we are committed today at home and around the world.  </p><p>Let every nation know, whether it wishes us well or ill, that we shall pay any price, bear any burden, meet any hardship, support any friend, oppose any foe, to assure the survival and the success of liberty.</p><p>This much we pledge – and more.</p><p>To those old allies whose cultural and spiritual origins we share, we pledge the loyalty of faithful friends. United there is little we cannot do in a host of cooperative ventures. Divided there is little we can do – for we dare not meet a powerful challenge at odds and split asunder.</p><p>To those new states whom we welcome to the ranks of the free, we pledge our word that one form of colonial control shall not have passed away merely to be replaced by a far more iron tyranny. We shall not always expect to find them supporting our view. But we shall always hope to find them strongly supporting their own freedom – and to remember that, in the past, those who foolishly sought power by riding the back of the tiger ended up inside. To those people in the huts and villages of half the globe struggling to break the bonds of mass misery, we pledge our best efforts to help them help themselves, for whatever period is required – not because the Communists may be doing it, not because we seek their votes,but because it is right. If a free society cannot help the many who are poor, it cannot save the few who are rich.</p><p>To our sister republics south of our border, we offer a special pledge: to convert our good words into good deeds, in a new alliance for progress, to assist free men and free governments in casting off the chains of poverty. But this peaceful revolution of hope cannot become the prey of hostile powers. Let all our neighbors know that we shall join with them to oppose aggression or subversion anywhere in the Americas. And let every other power know that this hemisphere intends to remain the master of its own house.</p><p>To that world assembly of sovereign states, the United Nations, our last best hope in an age where the instruments of war have far outpaced the instruments of peace, we renew our pledge of support – to prevent it from becoming merely a forum for invective, to strengthen its shield of the new and the weak, and to enlarge the area in which its writ may run.</p><p>Finally, to those nations who would make themselves our adversary, we offer not a pledge but a request: that both sides begin anew the quest for peace, before the dark powers of destruction unleashed by science engulf all humanity in planned or accidental self-destruction.</p><p>We dare not tempt them with weakness. For only when our arms are sufficient beyond doubt can we be certain beyond doubt that they will never be employed.  </p><p>But neither can two great and powerful groups of nations take comfort from our present course – both sides overburdened by the cost of modern weapons, both rightly alarmed by the steady spread of the deadly atom, yet both racing to alter that uncertain balance of terror that stays the hand of mankind’s final war.</p><p>So let us begin anew – remembering on both sides that civility is not a sign of weakness, and sincerity is always subject to proof. Let us never negotiate out of fear, but let us never fear to negotiate.</p><p>Let both sides explore what problems unite us instead of belaboring those problems which divide us.</p><p>Let both sides, for the first time, formulate serious and precise proposals for the inspection and control of arms, and bring the absolute power to destroy other nations under the absolute control of all nations.</p><p>Let both sides seek to invoke the wonders of science instead of its terrors. Together let us explore the stars, conquer the deserts, eradicate disease, tap the ocean depths, and encourage the arts and commerce.</p><p>Let both sides unite to heed, in all corners of the earth, the command of Isaiah – to “undo the heavy burdens, and [to] let the oppressed go free.”</p><p>And, if a beachhead of cooperation may push back the jungle of suspicion, let both sides join in creating a new endeavor – not a new balance of power, but a new world of law – where the strong are just, and the weak secure, and the peace preserved.</p><p>All this will not be finished in the first one hundred days. Nor will it be finished in the first one thousand days; nor in the life of this Administration; nor even perhaps in our lifetime on this planet. But let us begin.</p><p>In your hands, my fellow citizens, more than mine, will rest the final success or failure of our course. Since this country was founded, each generation of Americans has been summoned to give testimony to its national loyalty. The graves of young Americans who answered the call to service surround the globe.</p><p>Now the trumpet summons us again – not as a call to bear arms, though arms we need – not as a call to battle, though embattled we are – but a call to bear the burden of a long twilight struggle, year in and year out, “rejoicing in hope; patient in tribulation,” a struggle against the common enemies of man: tyranny, poverty, disease, and war itself.</p><p>Can we forge against these enemies a grand and global alliance, North and South, East and West, that can assure a more fruitful life for all mankind? Will you join in that historic effort?</p><p>In the long history of the world, only a few generations have been granted the role of defending freedom in its hour of maximum danger. I do not shrink from this responsibility – I welcome it. I do not believe that any of us would exchange places with any other people or any other generation. The energy, the faith, the devotion which we bring to this endeavor will light our country and all who serve it. And the glow from that fire can truly light the world. </p><p>And so, my fellow Americans, ask not what your country can do for you; ask what you can do for your country.</p><p>My fellow citizens of the world, ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man.</p><p>Finally,whether you are citizens of America or citizens of the world, ask of us here the same high standards of strength and sacrifice which we ask of you. With a good conscience our only sure reward, with history the final judge of our deeds, let us go forth to lead the land we love,asking His blessing and His help, but knowing that here on earth God’s work must truly be our own.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=753262888&amp;bvid=BV1zk4y167L2&amp;cid=197165599&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>千日紀事</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/%E5%8D%83%E6%97%A5%E7%B4%80%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/%E5%8D%83%E6%97%A5%E7%B4%80%E4%BA%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T09:45:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T09:51:48.701Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/aZdrF6ePhMGyv3Y.jpg" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><p>庚子年閏四月初八日。</p><p>晴空萬里</p><p>自2017-09-03到2020-05-30，已然走入大學達千日。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/aZdrF6ePhMGyv3Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>George W. Bush：911 Address to the Nation</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/George%20W.%20Bush%EF%BC%9A911%20Address%20to%20the%20Nation/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/George%20W.%20Bush%EF%BC%9A911%20Address%20to%20the%20Nation/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:50:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:19:00.197Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=838262311&bvid=BV1vg4y1B7bn&cid=196498473&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>Good evening.</p><p>Today, our fellow citizens, our way of life, our very freedom came under attack in a series of deliberate and deadly terrorist acts. The victims were in airplanes or in their offices: secretaries, business men and women, military and federal workers, moms and dads, friends and neighbors. Thousands of lives were suddenly ended by evil, despicable acts of terror. The pictures of airplanes flying into buildings, fires burning, huge ­­ huge structures collapsing have filled us with disbelief, terrible sadness, and a quiet, unyielding anger. These acts of mass murder were intended to frighten our nation into chaos and retreat. But they have failed. Our country is strong.</p><p>A great people has been moved to defend a great nation. Terrorist attacks can shake the foundations of our biggest buildings, but they cannot touch the foundation of America. These acts shatter steel, but they cannot dent the steel of American resolve. America was targeted for attack because we’re the brightest beacon for freedom and opportunity in the world. And no one will keep that light from shining. Today, our nation saw evil ­­ the very worst of human nature ­­ and we responded with the best of America. With the daring of our rescue workers,with the caring for strangers and neighbors who came to give blood and help in any way they could.</p><p>Immediately following the first attack, I implemented our government’s emergency response plans. Our military is powerful, and it’s prepared. Our emergency teams are working in New York City and Washington D.C. to help with local rescue efforts. Our first priority is to get help to those who have been injured, and to take every precaution to protect our citizens at home and around the world from further attacks. The functions of our government continue without interruption. Federal agencies in Washington which had to be evacuated today are reopening for essential personnel tonight and will be open for business tomorrow. Our financial institutions remain strong, and the American economy will be open for business as well.</p><p>The search is underway for those who were behind these evil acts. I have directed the full resources of our intelligence and law enforcement communities to find those responsible andto bring them to justice. We will make no distinction between the terrorists who committedthese acts and those who harbor them.</p><p>Iappreciate so very much the members of Congress who have joined me in strongly condemning these attacks. And on behalf of the American people, I thank the many world leaders who have called to offer their condolences and assistance. America and our friendsand allies join with all those who want peace and security in the world, and we stand togetherto win the war against terrorism.</p><p>Tonight, I ask for your prayers for all those who grieve, for the children whose worlds have been shattered, for all whose sense of safety and security has been threatened. And I pray they will be comforted by a Power greater than any of us, spoken through the ages in Psalm23: Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I fear no evil for you are with me.</p><p>This is a day when all Americans from every walk of life unite in our resolve for justice and peace. America has stood down enemies before, and we will do so this time. None of us will ever forget this day, yet we go forward to defend freedom and all that is good and just in our world.</p><p>Thank you. Good night. And God bless America.  </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=838262311&amp;bvid=BV1vg4y1B7bn&amp;cid=196498473&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Beautiful Mind - The Nobel Prize</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/A%20Beautiful%20Mind%20-%20The%20Nobel%20Prize/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/A%20Beautiful%20Mind%20-%20The%20Nobel%20Prize/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:48:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:39.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=840782239&bvid=BV1q54y1D7qq&cid=196323697&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=840782239&amp;bvid=BV1q54y1D7qq&amp;cid=196323697&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dilios&#39; Battle Call at Plataea</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Dilios&#39;%20Battle%20Call%20at%20Plataea/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Dilios&#39;%20Battle%20Call%20at%20Plataea/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:46:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:21.839Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=243340752&bvid=BV1kv411z7aD&cid=196323093&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=243340752&amp;bvid=BV1kv411z7aD&amp;cid=196323093&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>【梅豔芳】似是故人來</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%A2%85%E8%B1%94%E8%8A%B3%E3%80%91%E4%BC%BC%E6%98%AF%E6%95%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%BE%86/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%A2%85%E8%B1%94%E8%8A%B3%E3%80%91%E4%BC%BC%E6%98%AF%E6%95%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%BE%86/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T03:10:21.446Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T16:15:24.921Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=285790377&bvid=BV1Pf4y127GQ&cid=196286766&page=1&high_quality=1"  scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><p>深夜配老歌，明月在天。</p><a id="more"></a><p>昨日同可愛夜聊。聊到了許多老歌，如此夜晚，老歌更讓人回味。粵語保留了許多中古漢語的音調，聲調豐富，吟唱中文最合適不過。</p><p>初聽《似是故人來》，是洪塵的翻唱版，洪塵嗓音乾淨環味。若是要為自己那段時間做一首音樂註腳，莫過於這首《似是故人來》。林夕作詞，頗有長短句之韻。“恨臺上卿卿，或臺下我我，不是我跟你” 和 “斷腸字點點，風雨聲連連，似是故人來”，最是讓人絞腸。</p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=530 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=2&id=543747557&auto=0&height=66"></iframe><hr><center>作詞：林夕  作曲：羅大佑</center><center>同是過路，同做過夢</center><center>本應是一對</center><center>人在少年，夢中不覺</center><center>醒後要歸去</center><center>三餐一宿，也共一雙</center><center>到底會是誰</center><center>但凡未得到</center><center>但凡是過去</center><center>總是最登對</center><center>臺下你望，臺上我做</center><center>你想做的戲</center><center>前世故人，忘憂的你</center><center>可曾記得起</center><center>歡喜傷悲，老病生死</center><center>說不上傳奇</center><center>恨臺上卿卿</center><center>或臺下我我</center><center>不是我跟你</center><center>俗塵渺渺</center><center>天意茫茫</center><center>將你共我分開</center><center>斷腸字點點</center><center>風雨聲連連</center><center>似是故人來</center><center>何日再追，何地再醉</center><center>說今夜真美</center><center>無份有緣，回憶不斷</center><center>生命卻苦短</center><center>一種相思，兩段苦戀 </center><center>半生說沒完</center><center>在年月深淵</center><center>望明月遠遠</center><center>想像你憂鬱</center><center>俗塵渺渺</center><center>天意茫茫</center><center>將你共我分開</center><center>斷腸字點點</center><center>風雨聲連連</center><center>似是故人來</center><center>留下你或留下我</center><center>在世間上終老</center><center>離別以前</center><center>未知相對當日那麼好</center><center>執子之手</center><center>卻又分手</center><center>愛得有還無</center><center>十年後雙雙</center><center>萬年後對對</center><center>只恨看不到</center><center>十年後雙雙</center><center>萬年後對對</center><center>只恨看不到</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=285790377&amp;bvid=BV1Pf4y127GQ&amp;cid=196286766&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot;  scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;深夜配老歌，明月在天。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Queen Gorgo Address the Spartan Apella</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Queen%20Gorgo%20Address%20the%20Spartan%20Apella/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Queen%20Gorgo%20Address%20the%20Spartan%20Apella/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T01:59:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:17:10.770Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=837832074&bvid=BV1Pg4y1z7HL&cid=196258724&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true"sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>希波戰爭期間，波斯國王薛西斯一世親率30萬大軍征戰希臘，希臘防線最前線便是溫泉關，此處亦是波斯前往希臘的必經之路。叛徒出賣之後，斯巴達國王列奧尼達為保留希臘聯軍實力，讓聯軍先撤退，而自己率三百斯巴達勇士死守溫泉關。</p><p>視頻中，他的女人——斯巴達王后戈爾戈在兩軍交戰明顯己方處於劣勢的背景下，憑藉三寸之舌，以一國王后的傲然氣勢，說服議會出兵抗擊波斯，解救斯巴達勇士。</p><p>有件軼事能一窺戈爾戈的氣魄。有次戈爾戈訪問雅典，一個女人問她，為何斯巴達女人能控制住自己的男人。戈爾戈回答，因為只有斯巴達女人能生男人。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=837832074&amp;bvid=BV1Pg4y1z7HL&amp;cid=196258724&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>【浮生一紀】悲喜交加的故事</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%B5%AE%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%80%E7%B4%80%E3%80%91%E6%82%B2%E5%96%9C%E4%BA%A4%E5%8A%A0%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%B5%AE%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%80%E7%B4%80%E3%80%91%E6%82%B2%E5%96%9C%E4%BA%A4%E5%8A%A0%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T01:00:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:07.812Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710873160&bvid=BV1vQ4y1P7ni&cid=196205833&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true"sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710873160&amp;bvid=BV1vQ4y1P7ni&amp;cid=196205833&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>《共產黨宣言》1872年德文版序言</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/28/%E3%80%8A%E5%85%B1%E7%94%A2%E9%BB%A8%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80%E3%80%8B1872%E5%B9%B4%E5%BE%B7%E6%96%87%E7%89%88%E5%BA%8F%E8%A8%80/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/28/%E3%80%8A%E5%85%B1%E7%94%A2%E9%BB%A8%E5%AE%A3%E8%A8%80%E3%80%8B1872%E5%B9%B4%E5%BE%B7%E6%96%87%E7%89%88%E5%BA%8F%E8%A8%80/</id>
    <published>2020-05-28T09:57:35.228Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T00:53:07.523Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://tse2-mm.cn.bing.net/th/id/OIP.8ngFOLynf2yDDOdBfVbMXgHaFE?pid=Api&amp;rs=1" alt="查看源图像" style="zoom: 200%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>共產主義者同盟這個在當時條件下自然只能是秘密團體的國際工人組織， 1847年11月在倫敦舉行的代表大會上委託我們兩人起草一個準備公佈的詳細的理論和實踐的黨綱。 結果就產生了這個《宣言》 ， 《宣言》 原稿在二月革命前幾星期送到倫敦付印。 《宣言》 最初用德文出版， 它用這種文字在德國、 英國和美國至少印過12種不同的版本。 第一個英譯本是由海倫•麥克法林女士翻譯的， 於1850年在倫敦《紅色共和黨人》 雜誌上發表， 1871年至少又有三種不同的英譯本在美國出版。 法譯本於1848年六月起義前不久第一次在巴黎印行，最近又有法譯本在紐約《社會主義者報》 上發表；現在有人在準備新譯本。 波蘭文譯本在德文本初版問世後不久就在倫敦出現。 俄譯本是60年代在日內瓦出版的。 丹麥文譯本也是在原書問世後不久就出版了。</p><p>不管最近25年來的情況發生了多大的變化， 這個《宣言》 中所闡述的一般原理整個說來直到現在還是完全正確的。 某些地方本來可以作一些修改。 這些原理的實際運用， 正如《宣言》 中所說的， 隨時隨地都要以當時的歷史條件為轉移， 所以第二章末尾提出的那些革命措施根本沒有特別的意義。 如果是在今天， 這一段在許多方面都會有不同的寫法了。 由於最近25年來大工業有了巨大發展而工人階級的政黨組織也跟著發展起來， 由於首先有了二月革命的實際經驗而後來尤其是有了無產階級第一次掌握政權達兩月之久的巴黎公社的實際經驗， 所以這個綱領現在有些地方已經過時了。 特別是公社已經證明： “工人階級不能簡單地掌握現成的國家機器， 並運用它來達到自己的目的。 ” (見《法蘭西內戰。 國際工人協會總委員會宣言》 德文版第19頁， 那裡對這個思想作了更詳細的闡述。 ） 其次， 很明顯， 對於社會主義文獻所作的批判在今天看來是不完全的， 因為這一批判只包括到1847年為止， 同樣也很明顯， 關於共產黨人對待各種反對黨派的態度的論述(第四章)雖然在原則上今天還是正確的， 但是就其實際運用來說今天畢竟已經過時， 因為政治形勢已經完全改變， 當時所列舉的那些黨派大部分已被歷史的發展徹底掃除了。</p><p>不管最近25年來的情況發生了多大的變化， 這個《宣言》 中所闡述的一般原理整個說來直到現在還是完全正確的。 某些地方本來可以作一些修改。 這些原理的實際運用， 正如《宣言》 中所說的， 隨時隨地都要以當時的歷史條件為轉移， 所以第二章末尾提出的那些革命措施根本沒有特別的意義。 如果是在今天， 這一段在許多方面都會有不同的寫法了。 由於最近25年來大工業有了巨大發展而工人階級的政黨組織也跟著發展起來， 由於首先有了二月革命的實際經驗而後來尤其是有了無產階級第一次掌握政權達兩月之久的巴黎公社的實際經驗， 所以這個綱領現在有些地方已經過時了。 特別是公社已經證明： “工人階級不能簡單地掌握現成的國家機器， 並運用它來達到自己的目的。 ” (見《法蘭西內戰。 國際工人協會總委員會宣言》 德文版第19頁， 那裡對這個思想作了更詳細的闡述。 ） 其次， 很明顯， 對於社會主義文獻所作的批判在今天看來是不完全的， 因為這一批判只包括到1847年為止， 同樣也很明顯， 關於共產黨人對待各種反對黨派的態度的論述(第四章)雖然在原則上今天還是正確的， 但是就其實際運用來說今天畢竟已經過時， 因為政治形勢已經完全改變， 當時所列舉的那些黨派大部分已被歷史的發展徹底掃除了。</p><p>但是《宣言》 是一個歷史檔,我們已沒有權利來加以修改。 下次再版時也許能加上一篇論述1847年到現在這段時期的導言。 這次再版太倉促了， 我們來不及做這件工作。</p><p align="right">卡爾•馬克思 弗里德里希•恩格斯</p><p align="right">1872年6月24日於倫敦</p><p align="right">載於1872年在萊比錫出版的德文版《共產主義宣言》 一書</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://tse2-mm.cn.bing.net/th/id/OIP.8ngFOLynf2yDDOdBfVbMXgHaFE?pid=Api&amp;amp;rs=1&quot; alt=&quot;查看源图像&quot; style=&quot;zoom: 200%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>記一次LOGO設計</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/24/%E8%A8%98%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1LOGO%E8%A8%AD%E8%A8%88/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/24/%E8%A8%98%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1LOGO%E8%A8%AD%E8%A8%88/</id>
    <published>2020-05-24T10:36:03.334Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-28T10:24:55.008Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/28/BTjko2AmdUrbg85.png" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><a id="more"></a><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/24/NcSmuUQgH9eXIRZ.png" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><p>今日，給自己的網站設計了兩個LOGO，圖中有兩個元素。一隻貓頭鷹和德語單詞NICHTSEIN。貓頭鷹作爲的象徵，語出黑格爾的“密涅瓦的貓頭鷹”，以反思爲哲學特性。德語單詞NICHTSEIN由NICHT和SEIN組成，前者表示否定，後者指代存在，合起來的意思是不存在，也即“無”。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/28/BTjko2AmdUrbg85.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; style=&quot;zoom:150%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>滿目盡光</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/03/15/%E6%BB%BF%E7%9B%AE%E7%9B%A1%E5%85%89/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/03/15/%E6%BB%BF%E7%9B%AE%E7%9B%A1%E5%85%89/</id>
    <published>2020-03-15T08:11:01.654Z</published>
    <updated>2020-03-15T08:09:58.982Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://ae01.alicdn.com/kf/Ucaf3807ef37a43a7b3a5d9b1797980467.jpg" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><center>今日被這歌詞的旋律所繞樑。</center><center>Baby you’re my ONE and ONLY.</center><center>滿目星辰</center><center>明眸為月</center><center>縱使繁星點點在天</center><center>不若一雙明眸在前</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ae01.alicdn.com/kf/Ucaf3807ef37a43a7b3a5d9b1797980467.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sonnet 1</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/23/Sonnet%201/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/23/Sonnet%201/</id>
    <published>2020-02-23T15:25:43.606Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T15:27:19.879Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.pexels.com/photos/3643290/pexels-photo-3643290.jpeg?auto=compress&cs=tinysrgb&h=750&w=1260" alt="cemetery"></p><a id="more"></a><center>From fairest creatures we desire increase</center><center>That thereby the beauty’s rose might never die</center><center>But as the riper should by time decrease</center><center>His tender heir might bear his memory</center><center>But thou, contracted to thine own bright eyes</center><center>Feed’st thy light’s flame with self-substantial fuel</center><center>Making famine where abundance lies</center><center>Thyself thy foe, to thy sweet self too cruel</center><center>Thou that art now the world’s fresh ornament</center><center>And only herald to the gaudy spring</center><center>Within thine own bud buriest thy content</center><center>And, tender churl, mak’st waste in niggarding</center><center>Pity the world, or else this glutton be</center><center>To  eat the world’s due,  by grave and thee</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.pexels.com/photos/3643290/pexels-photo-3643290.jpeg?auto=compress&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;h=750&amp;w=1260&quot; alt=&quot;cemetery&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sonnet 73</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/22/Sonnet%2073/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/22/Sonnet%2073/</id>
    <published>2020-02-22T11:04:23.531Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-23T16:02:02.048Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://www.freeimageslive.co.uk/image/view/10960/_original" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><center>That time of year thou mayst in me behold</center><center>When yelloe leaves, or none, or few, do hang</center><center>Upon those boughs which shake against the cold</center><center>Bare ruined choirs, where late the sweet birds sang</center><center>In me thou seest the twilight of such day</center><center>As after sunset fadeth in the west</center><center>Which by and by black night doth take away</center><center>Death’s second self, that seals up all in rest</center><center>In me thou seest the glowing of such fire</center><center>That on the ashes of his youth doth lie</center><center>And the Death-bed whereon it must expire</center><center>Consumed with that which it was nourished by</center><center>This thou perceiv’st, which makes thy love more strong</center><center>To love that well, which thou must leave ere long</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.freeimageslive.co.uk/image/view/10960/_original&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sonnet 18</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/21/Sonnet%2018/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/21/Sonnet%2018/</id>
    <published>2020-02-21T12:50:40.574Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-21T12:50:18.932Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1570939276551-59a90ac1b80d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&w=1000&q=80" alt="Shakespeare and Company building during daytime"></p><a id="more"></a><center>Shall I compare thee to a summer’s day?</center><center>Thou art more lovely and more temperate:</center><center>Rough winds do shake the darling buds of May,</center><center>And summer’s lease hath all to short a date;</center><center>Sometime too hot the eye of heaven shines,</center><center>And often is his gold complexion dimmed;</center><center>And every fair from fair sometime declines,</center><center>By chance or nature’s changing course untrimmed:</center><center>But thy eternal summer shall not fade,</center><center>Nor lose possession of that fair thou ow’st,</center><center>Nor shall Death brag thou wand’rest in his shade,</center><center>When in eternal lines to time thou grow’st.</center><center>So long as men can breathe or eyes can see,</center><center>So long lives this, and this gives life to thee.</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1570939276551-59a90ac1b80d?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;w=1000&amp;q=80&quot; alt=&quot;Shakespeare and Company building during daytime&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Fight Against Injustice</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/14/The%20Fight%20Against%20Injustice/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/14/The%20Fight%20Against%20Injustice/</id>
    <published>2020-02-13T16:01:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-15T15:28:14.167Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://img.srgcdn.com/e/cVZoblh4ZkgxRzFWOGxUYW53alYuanBn.jpg" alt="查看源图像"></p><a id="more"></a><p>God, I’m full of so much gratitude right now. And I do not feel elevated above any of my fellow nominees or anyone in this room because we share the same love, the love of film. And this form of expression has given me the most extraordinary life. I don’t know what I’d be without it. But I think the greatest gift that it’s given me, and many of us in this room, is <strong>the opportunity to use our voice for the voiceless.</strong></p><p>I’ve been thinking a lot about some of the distressing issues that we are facing collectively. I think at times we feel, or we’re made to feel, that we champion different causes. But for me, I see commonality. I think, whether we’re talking about gender inequality or racism or queer rights or indigenous rights or animal rights, we’re talking about the fight against injustice. <strong>We’re talking about the fight against the belief that one nation, one people, one race, one gender or one species has the right to dominate, control and use and exploit another with impunity.</strong></p><p><img src="https://cdn.extra.ie/wp-content/uploads/2020/02/10074841/PRI136258495.jpg" alt="查看源图像"></p><p>I think that we’ve become very disconnected from the natural world, and many of us, what we’re guilty of is an egocentric world view — the belief that we’re the center of the universe. We go into the natural world, and we plunder it for its resources. We feel entitled to artificially inseminate a cow, and when she gives birth, we steal her baby, even though her cries of anguish are unmistakable. Then we take her milk that’s intended for her calf, and we put it in our coffee and our cereal. And I think we fear the idea of personal change because we think that we have to sacrifice something, to give something up, but human beings, at our best, are so inventive and creative and ingenious. And I think that when we use love and compassion as our guiding principles, we can create, develop and implement systems of change that are beneficial to all sentient beings and to the environment.</p><p>Now, I have been, I have been a scoundrel in my life. I’ve been selfish. I’ve been cruel at times, hard to work with, and I’m grateful that so many of you in this room have given me a second chance. <strong>And I think that’s when we’re at our best, when we support each other, not when we cancel each other out for past mistakes, but when we help each other to grow, when we educate each other, when we guide each other toward redemption. That is the best of humanity.</strong></p><p>When he was 17, my brother wrote this lyric. He said, “<strong>Run to the rescue with love, and peace will follow.</strong>”</p><hr><p><img src="http://cdn.collider.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/joaquin-phoenix-joker.jpg" alt="查看源图像"></p><p>演講者：<strong>Joaquin Phoenix</strong><br>譯    者：<strong>崑崙</strong></p><p>神吶，此刻我充滿著感激之情。我不認為在下比任一被提名者或在座各位來得高貴，因為我們同享一愛，對電影的愛。電影這一表達方式給了在下不一樣的人生。難以想象若無電影，我會如何。然於我所思，電影給予在下和在座各位最重要的禮物是——以吾之聲，代默者言。</p><p>鄙人已然思考著許多我們共同面臨的令人擔憂的事。思考我們注意到，或我們不得不注意，我們捍衛多樣的信仰。然於在下，吾所見者，共性也。吾思，不論我們談論性別平等、種族主義、同性戀權利、本土主義、動物權利，我們所言者，是謂與不公之鬥爭。我們所言者，乃與一國家、一個人、一種族、一性別、一物種擁有統治、管控、利用和剝削他者的權利而免於懲罰的觀念作鬥爭。</p><p>吾思，我們同此自然世界已然愈漸相隔，於多數人而言，所羞愧者乃自我中心的世界觀——人類是宇宙的中心。人類侵入自然，掠出資源。人類身懷給母牛人工授精之能，然當它一朝分娩，我們竊走它的孩兒，儘管清楚地望見它落下悲痛欲絕之淚。我們使用本該是餵養其幼仔的奶汁，倒入我們的咖啡和穀物食品。吾思，我們惶恐關乎個人轉變的觀念，因我們認為我們不得不為此做出一些犧牲、放棄一些事情，但我們人類，盡之天力，是如此富有創意、善於創造和足智多謀。吾思，當我們以愛和熱情作為導向原則，我們可以創造、發展和實行利於所有可感知生物和環境的轉變體系。</p><p>現在，我曾是，在人生中我曾是一個惡棍，也曾自私自利，有時冷酷粗暴，難以一同工作，在下十分感激在座各位予我第二次機會。吾思，當我們盡之全力，當我們相互支持，而非因過往錯誤而擯棄彼此，當我們助力彼此同進步，當我們互力為師，當我們互引彼此向救贖。此乃至上人性也。</p><p>當我哥哥17歲時，他著下此詩：“懷愛奔向救贖，安寧尾隨而來。”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img.srgcdn.com/e/cVZoblh4ZkgxRzFWOGxUYW53alYuanBn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;查看源图像&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>成都七中演講</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/11/%E6%88%90%E9%83%BD%E4%B8%83%E4%B8%AD%E6%BC%94%E8%AC%9B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/02/11/%E6%88%90%E9%83%BD%E4%B8%83%E4%B8%AD%E6%BC%94%E8%AC%9B/</id>
    <published>2020-02-11T14:29:49.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-02-12T14:38:38.784Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>林蔭校區的同學們，高新校區的同學們，網校的同學們：</p><p>你們好！</p><p>在這個非常時期，我很榮幸能代表我們語文備課組，和大家重聚在這個特殊的課堂裡。今天，我們以連線代替了會面、螢幕代替了黑板，雖然形式簡陋，但是我們為高三同學助力的熱情不変。</p><a id="more"></a><p>已經立春了，但今年的冬天卻似乎長得沒有盡頭。新冠肺炎還在肆虐，不知還有多少人正面臨著生離死別，還有多少家庭從此沒有明天。“時代的一粒灰，落在個人頭上，就是一座山。”對現在還掙扎在痛苦中的人們，談生活太奢侈了，有些時候，光是活著，就已經拼盡全力。</p><p>所以我們需要對眼前的苦難哀悼，感同身受地深深地哀悼。現在是未來的過去，我們對眼前的苦難哀悼是為了銘記。多年以後，春天來了又去，當陽光鋪灑在草地，當我們自由地呼吸空氣，當我們開心的歡聚，我們必須記得起若干年前，雪曾落在這片土地。死亡，是一個人的悲劇，遺忘是一個民族的悲劇。</p><p>我們還需要懺悔，因為真正的哀悼開始於懺悔。我們應當懺悔， 明明索爾仁尼琴的警告振聾發聵，我們卻裝聾作啞、卻隨波逐流， 甚至推波助瀾。最終，沒有人能夠置身事外。</p><p>魯迅先生曾經說過，墨寫的謊言掩蓋不住血寫的事實。“有的人，為了守住不會帶到棺材裡去的利益與權柄，在他們還活著的時候， 就因為貪婪而吞食了自己的心肝。當他們開始習慣性撒謊的時候， 也在將自己的親友與同胞推向深淵”。歷史不會因為無視而消失，責任也不能因為回避而逃脫。加繆在《鼠疫》中寫道:“這一切裡面並不存在英雄主義，這只是誠實的問題。與鼠疫鬥爭的唯一方式，只能是誠實。“</p><p>李文亮醫生走了，“我們憤怒於你的預警被當成謠言，我們傷慟於你的死亡竟不是謠言”。說真話的人，我們應該為他們豎碑，要有名有姓，拒絕一切匿名的紀念。</p><p>苦難必將過去，但我們不能把喪事當成喜事，不能把質疑換成讚歌，不能把追責偷換為免職。不能把冬天唱成春的開始，有些人已經埋在了冬天。</p><p>苦難必將過去，但僅止於哀悼和懺悔是不夠的，我們必須反省。</p><p>災難面前，最容易看清人性；一場瘟疫，撕下了誰出將入相的遮羞布？又有哪些媚骨在嘩眾取寵中撿拾著人血饅頭？</p><p>如何讓我們的孩子不成為這樣的人？如何能在下次災難來臨的時候，有更多的口罩，有更少的恐慌，有更多的擔當，有更少的推諉。</p><p>災難面前，也最容易看到人類內心深處的光芒。</p><p>哪些骨頭在風中挺立成了傲岸？哪些天使逆行走向了疫情最前線？哪些普通人的善良讓我們熱淚盈眶？哪些陌生人的溫暖讓我們重燃希望？</p><p>這些無懼無畏，這些不屈不撓，這些點點滴滴，讓我們看到了支撐這個民族歷盡滄桑，飽受磨難，依然屹立不倒的那根脊樑。</p><p>我們避免不了災難，我們卻能做好自己，我們預知不了未來，我們卻清晰的知道，未來在孩子們的手裡。</p><p>今天的這些數字，這些故事，這些人物，這些精神，這些教訓，這些反思，不能只出現在多年以後的課本裡，成為僵硬的答題要點。</p><p>這些真實的一切，應該讓孩子們知道。一張安靜的書桌來之不易，不能只安放沒有思想的大腦。</p><p>我們不是局外人，現在不是，未來更不是。因為，“無窮的遠方，無數的人們，都和我有關。”</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;林蔭校區的同學們，高新校區的同學們，網校的同學們：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;你們好！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在這個非常時期，我很榮幸能代表我們語文備課組，和大家重聚在這個特殊的課堂裡。今天，我們以連線代替了會面、螢幕代替了黑板，雖然形式簡陋，但是我們為高三同學助力的熱情不変。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
