<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Nichtsein</title>
  
  <subtitle>兩岸青山猶在 不見當年故人</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2020-06-06T04:27:38.191Z</updated>
  <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>崑崙</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>石原さとみ</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/06/%E7%9F%B3%E5%8E%9F%E3%81%95%E3%81%A8%E3%81%BF/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/06/%E7%9F%B3%E5%8E%9F%E3%81%95%E3%81%A8%E3%81%BF/</id>
    <published>2020-06-06T04:26:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-06T04:27:38.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=23693985&bvid=BV1cp411o7g4&cid=39584320&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=23693985&amp;bvid=BV1cp411o7g4&amp;cid=39584320&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; 
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>No Mistakes In The Tango</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/05/No-Mistakes-In-The-Tango/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/05/No-Mistakes-In-The-Tango/</id>
    <published>2020-06-05T15:57:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-05T15:58:23.111Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=455944615&bvid=BV1T5411W7FM&cid=199020532&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=455944615&amp;bvid=BV1T5411W7FM&amp;cid=199020532&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>芒種</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/05/%E8%8A%92%E7%A8%AE/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/05/%E8%8A%92%E7%A8%AE/</id>
    <published>2020-06-05T02:09:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-05T02:09:02.807Z</updated>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Franklin Delano Roosevelt：First Inaugural Address</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/05/Franklin-Delano-Roosevelt%EF%BC%9AFirst-Inaugural-Address/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/05/Franklin-Delano-Roosevelt%EF%BC%9AFirst-Inaugural-Address/</id>
    <published>2020-06-04T16:04:37.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-05T02:15:40.386Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="bilibili"><iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=498448312&bvid=BV1xK411p7RV&cid=198663065&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe></div><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>President Hoover, Mr. Chief Justice, my friends:</p><p>This is a day of national consecration. And I am certain that on this day my fellow Americans expect that on my induction into the Presidency, I will address them with a candor and a decision which the present situation of our people impels.</p><p>This is preeminently the time to speak the truth, the whole truth, frankly and boldly. Nor need we shrink from honestly facing conditions in our country today. This great Nation will endure, as it has endured, will revive and will prosper.</p><p>So, first of all, let me assert my firm belief that the only thing we have to fear is fear itself ­­ nameless, unreasoning, unjustified terror which paralyzes needed efforts to convert retreat into advance. In every dark hour of our national life, a leadership of frankness and of vigor has met with that understanding and support of the people themselves which is essential to victory. And I am convinced that you will again give that support to leadership in these critical days.</p><p>In such a spirit on my part and on yours we face our common difficulties. They concern, thank God, only material things. Values have shrunk to fantastic levels; taxes have risen; our ability to pay has fallen; government of all kinds is faced by serious curtailment of income; the means of exchange are frozen in the currents of trade; the withered leaves of industrial enterprise lie on every side; farmers find no markets for their produce; and the savings of many years in thousands of families are gone. More important, a host of unemployed citizens face the grim problem of existence, and an equally great number toil with little return. Only a foolish optimist can deny the dark realities of the moment.</p><p>And yet our distress comes from no failure of substance. We are stricken by no plague of locusts. Compared with the perils which our forefathers conquered, because they believed and were not afraid, we have still much to be thankful for. Nature still offers her bounty and human efforts have multiplied it. Plenty is at our doorstep, but a generous use of it languishes in the very sight of the supply.</p><p>Primarily, this is because the rulers of the exchange of mankind’s goods have failed, through their own stubbornness and their own incompetence, have admitted their failure, and have abdicated. Practices of the unscrupulous money changers stand indicted in the court of public opinion, rejected by the hearts and minds of men.</p><p>True, they have tried. But their efforts have been cast in the pattern of an outworn tradition. Faced by failure of credit, they have proposed only the lending of more money. Stripped of the lure of profit by which to induce our people to follow their false leadership, they have resorted to exhortations, pleading tearfully for restored confidence. They only know the rules of a generation of self­-seekers. They have no vision, and when there is no vision the people perish.</p><p>Yes, the money changers have fled from their high seats in the temple of our civilization. We may now restore that temple to the ancient truths. The measure of that restoration lies in the extent to which we apply social values more noble than mere monetary profit.</p><p>Happiness lies not in the mere possession of money; it lies in the joy of achievement, in the thrill of creative effort. The joy, the moral stimulation of work no longer must be forgotten in the mad chase of evanescent profits. These dark days, my friends, will be worth all they cost us if they teach us that our true destiny is not to be ministered unto but to minister to ourselves, to our fellow men.</p><p>Recognition of that falsity of material wealth as the standard of success goes hand in hand with the abandonment of the false belief that public office and high political position are to be valued only by the standards of pride of place and personal profit; and there must be an end to a conduct in banking and in business which too often has given to a sacred trust the likeness of callous and selfish wrongdoing. Small wonder that confidence languishes, for it thrives only on honesty, on honor, on the sacredness of obligations, on faithful protection, and on unselfish performance; without them it cannot live.</p><p>Restoration calls, however, not for changes in ethics alone. This Nation is asking for action, and action now.</p><p>Our greatest primary task is to put people to work. This is no unsolvable problem if we face it wisely and courageously. It can be accomplished in part by direct recruiting by the Government itself, treating the task as we would treat the emergency of a war, but at the same time, through this employment, accomplishing great ­­ greatly needed projects to stimulate and reorganize the use of our great natural resources.</p><p>Hand in hand with that we must frankly recognize the overbalance of population in our industrial centers and, by engaging on a national scale in a redistribution, endeavor to provide a better use of the land for those best fitted for the land.</p><p>Yes, the task can be helped by definite efforts to raise the values of agricultural products, and with this the power to purchase the output of our cities. It can be helped by preventing realistically the tragedy of the growing loss through foreclosure of our small homes and our farms. It can be helped by insistence that the Federal, the State, and the local governments act forthwith on the demand that their cost be drastically reduced. It can be helped by the unifying of relief activities which today are often scattered, uneconomical, unequal. It can be helped by national planning for and supervision of all forms of transportation and of communications and other utilities that have a definitely public character. There are many ways in which it can be helped, but it can never be helped by merely talking about it.</p><p>We must act. We must act quickly.</p><p>And finally, in our progress towards a resumption of work, we require two safeguards against a return of the evils of the old order. There must be a strict supervision of all banking and credits and investments. There must be an end to speculation with other people’s money. And there must be provision for an adequate but sound currency.</p><p>These, my friends, are the lines of attack. I shall presently urge upon a new Congress in special session detailed measures for their fulfillment, and I shall seek the immediate assistance of the 48 States.</p><p>Through this program of action we address ourselves to putting our own national house in order and making income balance outgo. Our international trade relations, though vastly important, are in point of time, and necessity, secondary to the establishment of a sound national economy. I favor, as a practical policy, the putting of first things first. I shall spare no effort to restore world trade by international economic readjustment; but the emergency at home cannot wait on that accomplishment.</p><p>The basic thought that guides these specific means of national recovery is not nationally ­­ narrowly nationalistic. It is the insistence, as a first consideration, upon the interdependence of the various elements in and parts of the United States of America ­­ a recognition of the old and permanently important manifestation of the American spirit of the pioneer. It is the way to recovery. It is the immediate way. It is the strongest assurance that recovery will endure.</p><p>In the field of world policy, I would dedicate this Nation to the policy of the good neighbor: the neighbor who resolutely respects himself and, because he does so, respects the rights of others; the neighbor who respects his obligations and respects the sanctity of his agreements in and with a world of neighbors.</p><p>If I read the temper of our people correctly, we now realize, as we have never realized before, our interdependence on each other; that we can not merely take, but we must give as well; that if we are to go forward, we must move as a trained and loyal army willing to sacrifice for the good of a common discipline, because without such discipline no progress can be made, no leadership becomes effective.</p><p>We are, I know, ready and willing to submit our lives and our property to such discipline, because it makes possible a leadership which aims at the larger good. This, I propose to offer, pledging that the larger purposes will bind upon us, bind upon us all as a sacred obligation with a unity of duty hitherto evoked only in times of armed strife.</p><p>With this pledge taken, I assume unhesitatingly the leadership of this great army of our people dedicated to a disciplined attack upon our common problems.</p><p>Action in this image, action to this end is feasible under the form of government which we have inherited from our ancestors. Our Constitution is so simple, so practical that it is possible always to meet extraordinary needs by changes in emphasis and arrangement without loss of essential form. That is why our constitutional system has proved itself the most superbly enduring political mechanism the modern world has ever seen.</p><p>It has met every stress of vast expansion of territory, of foreign wars, of bitter internal strife, of world relations. And it is to be hoped that the normal balance of executive and legislative authority may be wholly equal, wholly adequate to meet the unprecedented task before us.</p><p>But it may be that an unprecedented demand and need for undelayed action may call for temporary departure from that normal balance of public procedure.</p><p>I am prepared under my constitutional duty to recommend the measures that a stricken nation in the midst of a stricken world may require. These measures, or such other measures as the Congress may build out of its experience and wisdom, I shall seek, within my constitutional authority, to bring to speedy adoption.</p><p>But, in the event that the Congress shall fail to take one of these two courses, in the event that the national emergency is still critical, I shall not evade the clear course of duty that will then confront me. I shall ask the Congress for the one remaining instrument to meet the crisis</p><p>­­ broad Executive power to wage a war against the emergency, as great as the power that would be given to me if we were in fact invaded by a foreign foe.</p><p>For the trust reposed in me, I will return the courage and the devotion that befit the time. I can do no less.</p><p>We face the arduous days that lie before us in the warm courage of national unity; with the clear consciousness of seeking old and precious moral values; with the clean satisfaction that comes from the stern performance of duty by old and young alike. We aim at the assurance of a rounded, a permanent national life.</p><p>We do not distrust the ­­ the future of essential democracy. The people of the United States have not failed. In their need they have registered a mandate that they want direct, vigorous action. They have asked for discipline and direction under leadership. They have made me the present instrument of their wishes. In the spirit of the gift I take it.</p><p>In this dedication ­­ In this dedication of a Nation, we humbly ask the blessing of God. May He protect each and every one of us.</p><p>May He guide me in the days to come.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;div class=&quot;bilibili&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=498448312&amp;bvid=BV1xK411p7RV&amp;cid=198663065&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Make this Moment the Turning Point for Real Change</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/04/How-to-Make-this-Moment-the-Turning-Point-for-Real-Change/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/04/How-to-Make-this-Moment-the-Turning-Point-for-Real-Change/</id>
    <published>2020-06-04T14:40:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-04T14:43:24.346Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://miro.medium.com/max/1600/1*NStvOGnrBWCu9U13uKBMLA.jpeg" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><p>WRITTEN BY Barack Obama</p><p>&emsp;</p><p>As millions of people across the country take to the streets and raise their voices in response to the killing of George Floyd and the ongoing problem of unequal justice, many people have reached out asking how we can sustain momentum to bring about real change.</p><p>Ultimately, it’s going to be up to a new generation of activists to shape strategies that best fit the times. But I believe there are some basic lessons to draw from past efforts that are worth remembering.</p><p>First, the waves of protests across the country represent a genuine and legitimate frustration over a decades-long failure to reform police practices and the broader criminal justice system in the United States. The overwhelming majority of participants have been peaceful, courageous, responsible, and inspiring. They deserve our respect and support, not condemnation — something that police in cities like Camden and Flint have commendably understood.</p><p>On the other hand, the small minority of folks who’ve resorted to violence in various forms, whether out of genuine anger or mere opportunism, are putting innocent people at risk, compounding the destruction of neighborhoods that are often already short on services and investment and detracting from the larger cause. I saw an elderly black woman being interviewed today in tears because the only grocery store in her neighborhood had been trashed. If history is any guide, that store may take years to come back. So let’s not excuse violence, or rationalize it, or participate in it. <em>If we want our criminal justice system, and American society at large, to operate on a higher ethical code, then we have to model that code ourselves</em>.</p><p>Second, I’ve heard some suggest that the recurrent problem of racial bias in our criminal justice system proves that only protests and direct action can bring about change, and that voting and participation in electoral politics is a waste of time. I couldn’t disagree more. The point of protest is to raise public awareness, to put a spotlight on injustice, and to make the powers that be uncomfortable; in fact, throughout American history, it’s often only been in response to protests and civil disobedience that the political system has even paid attention to marginalized communities. But eventually, <em>aspirations have to be translated into specific laws and institutional practices</em> — and in a democracy, that only happens when we elect government officials who are responsive to our demands.</p><p>Moreover, it’s important for us to understand <em>which</em> levels of government have the biggest impact on our criminal justice system and police practices. When we think about politics, a lot of us focus only on the presidency and the federal government. And yes, we should be fighting to make sure that we have a president, a Congress, a U.S. Justice Department, and a federal judiciary that actually recognize the ongoing, corrosive role that racism plays in our society and want to do something about it. <em>But the elected officials who matter most in reforming police departments and the criminal justice system work at the state and local levels</em>.</p><p>It’s mayors and county executives that appoint most police chiefs and negotiate collective bargaining agreements with police unions. It’s district attorneys and state’s attorneys that decide whether or not to investigate and ultimately charge those involved in police misconduct. Those are all elected positions. In some places, police review boards with the power to monitor police conduct are elected as well. Unfortunately, voter turnout in these local races is usually pitifully low, especially among young people — which makes no sense given the direct impact these offices have on social justice issues, not to mention the fact that who wins and who loses those seats is often determined by just a few thousand, or even a few hundred, votes.</p><p>So the bottom line is this: if we want to bring about real change, then the choice isn’t between protest and politics. <em>We have to do both.</em> We have to mobilize to raise awareness, <em>and</em> we have to organize and cast our ballots to make sure that we elect candidates who will act on reform.</p><p>Finally, <em>the more specific we can make demands for criminal justice and police reform, the harder it will be for elected officials to just offer lip service to the cause and then fall back into business as usual once protests have gone away</em>. The content of that reform agenda will be different for various communities. A big city may need one set of reforms; a rural community may need another. Some agencies will require wholesale rehabilitation; others should make minor improvements. Every law enforcement agency should have clear policies, including an independent body that conducts investigations of alleged misconduct. Tailoring reforms for each community will require local activists and organizations to do their research and educate fellow citizens in their community on what strategies work best.</p><p>But as a starting point, here’s a <a href="https://www.obama.org/wp-content/uploads/Toolkit.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">report and toolkit</a> developed by the Leadership Conference on Civil and Human Rights and based on the work of the Task Force on 21st Century Policing that I formed when I was in the White House. And if you’re interested in taking concrete action, we’ve also created a dedicated <a href="https://www.obama.org/anguish-and-action/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">site</a> at the Obama Foundation to aggregate and direct you to useful resources and organizations who’ve been fighting the good fight at the local and national levels for years.</p><p>I recognize that these past few months have been hard and dispiriting — that the fear, sorrow, uncertainty, and hardship of a pandemic have been compounded by tragic reminders that prejudice and inequality still shape so much of American life. But watching the heightened activism of young people in recent weeks, of every race and every station, makes me hopeful. If, going forward, we can channel our justifiable anger into peaceful, sustained, and effective action, then this moment can be a real turning point in our nation’s long journey to live up to our highest ideals.</p><p>Let’s get to work.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/max/1600/1*NStvOGnrBWCu9U13uKBMLA.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Coronavirus Will Reshape the World Order in China&#39;s Favor</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/04/Coronavirus%20Will%20Reshape%20the%20World%20Order%20in%20China&#39;s%20Favor/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/04/Coronavirus%20Will%20Reshape%20the%20World%20Order%20in%20China&#39;s%20Favor/</id>
    <published>2020-06-04T10:07:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-04T10:32:24.385Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/06/04/vmUGHxieg8LhVYq.png" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>For the motion</p><ul><li>Following its domestic response to the COVID-19 outbreak, China positioned itself as a global leader by sending medical supplies and personnel to nations struggling to contain the virus. </li><li>The United States is abdicating its leadership role as the global superpower. Rather than coordinating a multilateral response and working alongside the World Health Organization, Washington has embraced “America First,” stepping away from international alliances and outbidding allies for medical supplies. </li><li>China and India have been the world’s largest economies for 1,800 of the past 2,000 years. The modern American-led world order is not guaranteed. </li></ul><p>Against the motion</p><ul><li>The international community has criticized the Chinese Communist Party for suppressing news about coronavirus and silencing whistleblowers. This raises concerns about Xi Jinping’s credibility and China’s reputation on the world stage. </li><li>China does not have the economic capacity to fill the American leadership vacuum. After investing in the costly Belt and Road Initiative, the Chinese government faces growing debt. Further, a looming global recession promises to undermine China’s influence at home and abroad. </li><li>The pandemic has highlighted the drawbacks of global supply chains based in China. As countries reshore manufacturing, China risks losing trade opportunities and economic influence. Meanwhile, the dollar remains the dominant world currency. </li></ul>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/06/04/vmUGHxieg8LhVYq.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Debates" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Debates/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>青龍過海</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/02/%E9%9D%92%E9%BE%8D%E9%81%8E%E6%B5%B7/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/02/%E9%9D%92%E9%BE%8D%E9%81%8E%E6%B5%B7/</id>
    <published>2020-06-02T15:52:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-03T02:32:36.565Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="http://file.youboy.com/a/28/89/89/2/1118672.jpg" alt="查看源图像" style="zoom:200%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>今天吃飯的時候，突然想到一件事。</p><p>初中時跟二姑丈一起吃飯，當時的飯桌上有一盤空心菜，這時候我二姑丈就問我：“阿昆，你知不知道空心菜有個別稱？”孤陋寡聞的我怎會知道空心菜還有個別稱。</p><p>然後二姑丈說：“叫‘青龍過海’，因為空心菜長在水面上的樣子如同一條青龍盤在海上，故有此別稱。粵語中叫青龍過海（粵語音：xing龍過海）。”</p><p>聽後我一拍大腿，妙哉。果然勞動人民的智慧是無窮的。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;http://file.youboy.com/a/28/89/89/2/1118672.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;查看源图像&quot; style=&quot;zoom:200%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="庚子紀實" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E7%B4%80%E5%AF%A6/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>談“現實的個人”</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/02/%E6%B7%BA%E8%AB%87%E2%80%9C%E7%8F%BE%E5%AF%A6%E7%9A%84%E5%80%8B%E4%BA%BA%E2%80%9D/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/02/%E6%B7%BA%E8%AB%87%E2%80%9C%E7%8F%BE%E5%AF%A6%E7%9A%84%E5%80%8B%E4%BA%BA%E2%80%9D/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T16:19:05.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-03T03:51:48.878Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://www.tnm.jp/uploads/fckeditor/exhibition/special/2012/kokyu/uid000071_201112141943542854ed86.jpg" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>就費爾巴哈哲學而言，確立起感性確定性，以感性確定性的方式切入現實。不同于以黑格爾哲學為代表的唯心主義，將人做抽象化處理，以頭腦思辨的方式去理解和解釋世界，這時的人是思想體系中的人。費爾巴哈重新拾起唯物主義原則，將主詞切換到具體和現實的存在，觀念從屬於賓詞。費爾巴哈對此前的哲學立場做了顛倒處理。但是費爾巴哈是在感性直觀的基礎上建立起感性確定性，如此一來，費爾巴哈僅是看到存在本身所呈現出來的面目，他沒有能夠從過程本身來理解存在，而僅僅是過程終結是的面目來切入去解釋存在。即費爾巴哈沒有能夠對人的活動和存在本身做成對象性活動，未能建立其以否定性為原則的辯證法視角。而馬克思對費的更新在於，一方面，馬克思繼承了費爾巴哈關於唯物主義的思路和線索，另一方面，馬克思揚棄的費爾巴哈的感性直觀，同時引入了辯證法的否定性作用，把人的活動和存在展開為對象性活動，做成是一個具體的、現實的過程。</p><p>馬克思在《德意志意識形態》中談到“人的現實性”：“他們的活動和他們的物質生活條件，包括他們已有的和由他們自己的活動創造出來的物質生活條件。”馬克思從兩個因素來談論人的現實性，一方面是具體的現實的人，這是作為實際存在的個人，而非是思辨思想中的個人，另一方面，是人的物質生產生活條件，這是作為現實存在的個人的存在前提。馬克思還提到：“全部人類歷史的第一個前提無疑是有生命的個人的存在。”人的物理性存在無疑是關於人的一切的前提。“人們用以生產自己的生活資料的方式， 首先取決於他們已有的和需要再生產的生活資料本身的特性。 這種生產方式不應當只從它是個人肉體存在的再生產這方面加以考察， 更確切地說， 它是這些個人的一定的活動方式， 是他們表現自己生命的一定方式、 他們的一定的生活方式。”人掌握、使用生存資料的過程就是人的活動過程，人在現實的、已被創造出的物質條件上進行再生存創造，人的生存、條件、過程和結果都是呈現出實實在在的現實性。因此，是人的創造和生產“生產”出了人的歷史。</p><p>馬克思哲學在關於“現實的人”的解讀中，筆者認為馬克思十分強調人的現實的物質性生產和再創造，以一個過程及其後續性影響的視角來看待歷史本身。一方面他批判了唯心主義的抽象的個人，確立起人的現實性。但另一方面，馬克思對待人類這樣一個有別於其他動物，能自覺生產勞動的生物的視角上，筆者認為，馬克思更關注人的生物性和物理性表現，即人活生生地表現出來的現實的物理活動，但人就存在及其活動，思想性存在也同樣是現實的存在。它體現于人自我勞動時的對其勞動本身的頭腦刻畫。也即，理論和現實的一致性，人的物質生產過程就是其思想生產過程，而非現實之後的反思性加工思考才可稱之為思想。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.tnm.jp/uploads/fckeditor/exhibition/special/2012/kokyu/uid000071_201112141943542854ed86.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; style=&quot;zoom:150%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Philosophy" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Philosophy/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>庚子閏四月初十日｜記</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E9%96%8F%E5%9B%9B%E6%9C%88%E5%88%9D%E5%8D%81%E6%97%A5%E8%A8%98/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E9%96%8F%E5%9B%9B%E6%9C%88%E5%88%9D%E5%8D%81%E6%97%A5%E8%A8%98/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T13:54:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-03T02:24:11.611Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/06/02/McqJdy2n6P5E7VC.jpg" alt="img" style="zoom: 200%;" /><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>今日，晴，炎熱。</p><p>午後收到一位朋友發來的好消息，他博士面試通過了。實際上這是第二次考核，第一次因為意外狀況，沒能成功。也因此受到冷言諷語，在去年將近一年的時間裏，整個人都處於十分焦慮的狀態。仍記得回顧上學期期末，和他兩人夜遊校園。當時兩個人狀態相仿，那一次夜遊頗有感傷之情。仍記得，那時他說若是博士面試通過，他便將其詩集出版。當時我還開玩笑：“好，到時候我來寫序言。”那朗朗笑聲縈繞耳邊。</p><p>外部框架下的個人被牢牢鉗制，主客體已然顛倒，或多或少地程序式前進。被大浪潮裹挾著的各個個體作出非自由的決定。</p><p>有人星夜趕科場，有人辭官歸故里。仕途如此，學歷亦如此。另一位朋友，考研複試面試未去，現計劃北漂兼陪女友。在市民社會下，人與人之間的特殊性盡情顯露，為到普遍性，八仙過海，各顯神通，手段盡顯。</p><p>不論如何，都要善於在各自的道路限制自己，正是“衣帶漸寬終不悔，為伊消得人憔悴”。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/06/02/McqJdy2n6P5E7VC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot; style=&quot;zoom: 200%;&quot; /&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="庚子紀實" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E7%B4%80%E5%AF%A6/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Forever Young</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/Forever%20Young/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/Forever%20Young/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T13:37:35.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-02T05:26:24.974Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/914HddyUgwL.jpg" alt="img"></p><center>May you always be forever young.</center><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>今日是兒童節，首先來欣賞三首與兒童有關的詩詞。感受一下古人筆下孩童的天真無邪與青春美好。</p><p>&emsp;</p><center>池上二絕·其二</center><center>白居易</center>&emsp;<center>小娃撐小艇，</center><center>偷採白蓮回。</center><center>不解藏蹤跡，</center><center>浮萍一道開。</center><p>&emsp;<br>&emsp;</p><center>清平樂·檢校山園林書所見</center><center>辛棄疾</center>&emsp;<center>連雲松竹，</center><center>萬事從今足。</center><center>拄杖東家分社肉，</center><center>白酒床頭初熟。</center><center>西風梨棗山園，</center><center>兒童偷把長竿。</center><center>莫遣旁人驚去，</center><center>老夫靜處閒看。</center><p>&emsp;<br>&emsp;</p><center>村居</center><center>高鼎</center>&emsp;<center>草長鶯飛二月天，</center><center>拂堤楊柳醉春煙。</center><center>兒童散學歸來早，</center><center>忙趁東風放紙鳶。</center><p>&emsp;</p><p>&emsp;</p><hr><p>&emsp;</p><p>接下來欣賞音樂。第一位是意外在網易雲音樂上發現的博主，初次聽到折服於其聲線，溫柔甜美。後來感受到的是她對於美國民謠的喜歡，做了上百期播客，在她身上不難看到那種對音樂的純粹興趣。</p><p>這首歌是Bob Dylan 的 <em>Forever Young</em> ，正是應和今日主題。</p><p>&emsp;</p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=460 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=3&id=2067410056&auto=0&height=66"></iframe>&emsp;<p>&emsp;</p><p>第二首是縱貫線的《童年》，來自2010年的演唱會。</p><p>&emsp;</p><iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=625912689&bvid=BV15t4y1y7hh&cid=197589280&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://images-na.ssl-images-amazon.com/images/I/914HddyUgwL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;May you always be forever young.&lt;/center&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="庚子紀實" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E7%B4%80%E5%AF%A6/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>市民社會非倫理化的根源及其後果</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/%E5%B8%82%E6%B0%91%E7%A4%BE%E6%9C%83%E9%9D%9E%E5%80%AB%E7%90%86%E5%8C%96%E7%9A%84%E6%A0%B9%E6%BA%90%E5%8F%8A%E5%85%B6%E5%BE%8C%E6%9E%9C/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/06/01/%E5%B8%82%E6%B0%91%E7%A4%BE%E6%9C%83%E9%9D%9E%E5%80%AB%E7%90%86%E5%8C%96%E7%9A%84%E6%A0%B9%E6%BA%90%E5%8F%8A%E5%85%B6%E5%BE%8C%E6%9E%9C/</id>
    <published>2020-06-01T10:16:29.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-03T01:24:44.673Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img2.chinadaily.com.cn/images/202003/07/5e631587a310128206596ab9.jpeg" alt="查看源图像"></p><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>本文對這一論題的切入點有兩點：一、需求體系在市民社會中所產生的作用和影響；二、市民社會與其所處的三重結構之間的相互關係。</p><p>市民社會是家庭和國家之間的中介，是個人組成的家庭和作為共同體的國家之間緩衝地帶。在市民社會的構成上，個人的活動範圍從家庭擴大到社會，在社會中人成了原子式個人，人與人之間的聯繫是相互成就的。在封建貴族制度的體系瓦解之下，早期資產階級分子在社會變革中發揮這個階層特有的作用。這一時期所有制從對於地產（不動產）的佔有轉變為對於動產的佔有。私有制得到進一步的發展，隨著新的階層力量在社會上不斷建立屬於該階層的活動原則，也即是該階層的普遍性逐步展開的過程。私有制和市場化的交織之下，個人從家庭被帶到市場中，逐步同社會的其他人打交道。因此，在個人彼此之間、個人同社會共同體之間的關係被不斷被塑造，發展為原子式個人之間的聯繫和個人和共同體聯繫。但人之間的聯繫自一開始就是以需求為導向的，作為特殊性的原子式個人參與社會活動，無疑是為了滿足自身的利益需求。整個社會活動以特殊性的主體原則出發，在這個情況下，外部框架的主體原則並沒有強力建立起來，即國家的對於個人的強制性為成為固定化的程式。這就使得特殊性利益是淩駕於普遍利益之上的。</p><p>市民社會的第一個環節是需求體系，需求體系推動了市民社會這一“機器”的運轉。在市民社會的結構中，個人需求的驅動帶來的勞動的發展，滿足個人需求的方式中需要勞動的展開。需求的多樣性和勞動工具和方式的發展相互交織帶來了分工。資本的參與讓人與人之間越發出現階層分野，社會財富出現集聚性，展現出個人特殊性的膨脹方面的現實體現。一方面，需求體系是市民社會得以自我建構的基礎，需求體系使得個人跨越地域、民族、階層等一切阻礙發生聯繫，市民社會中建構起新的人與人之間的聯繫。另一方面，需求體系在市民社會中的地位恰恰體現出特殊性高於普遍性狀態，因為人之間的聯繫無不是以滿足特殊性自我需求為活動前提的，這就讓人與人之間的關係變得單一和脆弱，讓貨幣關係而非其他關係支配人與人之間的關係。</p><p>如此一來，我們可以看到如下的情況：一方面，在市民社會這一“現實機器”得以運轉的前提是作為每一個環節的個人的活動同他人活動的相互展開和彼此成就，但是一旦特殊性利益的追求過程遭到阻礙，那麼市民社會就缺少了現實的內在動力。並且此時作為更大共同體的國家因缺少足夠強力的主體原則，難以施力于市民社會。另一方面，市民社會是以私有制和自願交換為基礎的市場經濟社會，個人的特殊性和主觀性不斷塑造和個體的社會地位和社會角色，但需要注意的是，社會中不同個體的特殊性和主觀性因素是不一樣的，也即各個人在自由的市場經濟中不是持有同一元素發展的，這就造成在原子式個人經過市民社會的作用之後，呈現出紛繁複雜的現實成像。</p><p>在家庭-市民社會-國家的三重結構中，家庭被外部現實壓制，人被迫甩出家庭，人與人之間的關係由親緣關係向利益-需求關係轉變。國家的主體原則和外部框架還沒建立起來，難以發揮強力的國家手段。在兩頭弱的情況下，市民社會力量壯大，建立其主體原則和發揮其手段。在特殊性原則的支撐下，貨幣展現出其龐大的力量。利益關係凝結著市民社會的原子式個人，又把彼此打散。人的利益和需求越發成為個人活動的首要原則，特殊性越發膨脹，普遍性越發抽象，甚至失去現實性。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img2.chinadaily.com.cn/images/202003/07/5e631587a310128206596ab9.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;查看源图像&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Philosophy" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Philosophy/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>冒險家的浪漫：從亨利王子到伊隆馬斯克</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/31/%E5%86%92%E9%9A%AA%E5%AE%B6%E7%9A%84%E6%B5%AA%E6%BC%AB%EF%BC%9A%E5%BE%9E%E4%BA%A8%E5%88%A9%E7%8E%8B%E5%AD%90%E5%88%B0%E4%BC%8A%E9%9A%86%E9%A6%AC%E6%96%AF%E5%85%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/31/%E5%86%92%E9%9A%AA%E5%AE%B6%E7%9A%84%E6%B5%AA%E6%BC%AB%EF%BC%9A%E5%BE%9E%E4%BA%A8%E5%88%A9%E7%8E%8B%E5%AD%90%E5%88%B0%E4%BC%8A%E9%9A%86%E9%A6%AC%E6%96%AF%E5%85%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-31T03:35:31.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-03T14:39:51.017Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/rxNsgDGwjpUd71z.png" alt="img"></p><blockquote><p>Open your eyes, look up to the skies.</p><p align="right">——Elon Musk</p></blockquote><a id="more"></a><p>&emsp;</p><p>&emsp;</p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/SvjHpwXYIqQZnl9.png" alt="img" style="zoom:150%;" /><center>Elon Musk的推文</center>&emsp;<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/yNqVY35GFztJdKg.png" alt="img"></p><center>Bob Behnken和Doug Hurley在火箭前合影，當真屬男人間的浪漫</center><p>&emsp;</p><p>初中時的我看紀錄片《大國崛起》，瞭解到葡萄牙奔向地理大發現背後的推動者。這位被譽為“航海王子”的推動者，終其一生只有四次航海行動，並且只是在熟悉的近海活動。 但“航海王子”的美譽不為過，因為亨利一手推動葡萄牙成為人類新遠征的領航者。</p><p>15世紀中葉，受到奧斯曼土耳其帝國的阻擋，東西方商路受阻。為到達東方尋找黃金，擴充資本。在強大的利益驅使下，以皇室為代表的資本投資方將資本押到國運的賭注上。1487年，葡萄牙航海家迪亞士揚帆起航，直抵非洲大陸最南端——好望角。1492年，意大利航海家哥倫布率領三艘航船，來到美洲大陸；1498年，葡萄牙航海家達·伽馬沿着迪亞士開闢的航路到達印度。1519年~1522年，葡萄牙航海家麥哲倫完成環球航行。</p><p>西方航海家以其強大的使命感和冒險精神，揚帆衝向茫茫大海，將人類的活動與聯繫在全球範圍內展開。資本跟在航海家的船後，抵達世界各個民族和角落，貨幣的氣息逐漸在藍色星球上瀰漫開來，貿易隨之而來。舊的關係被搗毀，利益-需求原則新的成為主導世界的原則。</p><p>回看飽受盛譽的鄭和，率領龐大七下西洋，最遠達到非洲東岸。但是這樣的揚帆遠航不過是以虧空國庫為代價，為的是“懷柔遠邦”，以彰顯天朝大國的風範罷了，除此以外，別無他用。鄭和去世後，鑑於遠洋所消耗的巨大開支，及其所引起明朝各個利益方之間的衝突，有的官員將大型航船寶船福船的建造資料付之一炬。隨後，古代中國也再沒有如此大規模遠洋活動。反而實行海禁，沿岸居民內遷十里，以絕海患。同遼闊的世界隔絕開來，夜郎自大。</p><p>&emsp;</p><p><img src="https://www.geekyexplorer.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/lisbon-3-day-itinerary-padrao-descobrimentos-what-to-see-and-do-lisbon.jpg" alt="See the source image"></p><center>航海紀念碑上的亨利王子 |  Prince Henry the Navigator</center><p>&emsp;</p><img src="https://www.biography.com/.image/t_share/MTMxNDk1NDE5MDgyNDgwMDk0/henry-the-navigator-2jpg.jpg" alt="Henry The Navigator Photo" style="zoom:67%;" /><center>“D. Henrique Infante de Portugal,” from The Library at The Mariners’ Museum</center><p>&emsp;</p><iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=370943629&bvid=BV1wZ4y1H79h&cid=198323506&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>&emsp;<p>隨着新大陸的貴重金屬源源不斷地流入伊比利亞半島，葡萄牙和西班牙皇室愈發沉溺於奢靡生活。世界精神開始先後轉移到荷蘭與英國。在新時期的世界遠征中，舞臺中央的角色不是國家意識，而是企業家精神。荷蘭東印度公司（Dutch East India Company）與大英東印度公司（English East India Company）先後藉助資本一路披荊斬棘，跑馬圈地。</p><p>&emsp;</p><iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710962015&bvid=BV1sD4y1D7aK&cid=198244002&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><p>&emsp;</p><img src="https://cdn.britannica.com/s:700x500/06/113706-004-55D378D9/East-India-House-London-Leadenhall-Street-Thomas-1817.jpg" alt="East India House, London" style="zoom:150%;" /><center>East India House, London </center><center>The East India House in Leadenhall Street, London, drawing by Thomas Hosmer Shepherd, c. 1817.Thomas Hosmer Shepherd</center><p>&emsp;</p><iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=200951369&bvid=BV1nz411i7hh&cid=198198338&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><p>從東印度公司，到Space X，新的領域遠征中，市場主體代替國家意志成為新領域的操盤手。強力的使命感背後是龐大的市場做支撐，創造市場最好的辦法就是把它做出來。</p><p>&emsp;</p><hr><p>&emsp;</p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/06/02/E5Dfp1txZQGquPb.jpg" alt="img" style="zoom:200%;" /><p>藝術家Tristan Eaton做的版畫《Human Kind》跟隨Falcon 9上太空 ，分別代表著人類的過去和未來。在這兩張蒙太奇版畫中，我們看到以下元素：黑猩猩和它的孩子、土星五號月球火箭、核裂變、伸出的手、鴿子、睡蓮、和平符號、鸚鵡螺的貝殼、笑臉。</p><p>左側有一行小字 “Small steps lead to giant leaps.”。</p><p>&emsp;</p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/06/02/mCsjIU62GNLSz1b.jpg" alt="img" style="zoom:200%;" />]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/rxNsgDGwjpUd71z.png&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open your eyes, look up to the skies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;——Elon Musk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>John F. Kennedy：Presidential Inaugural Address</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/John%20F.%20Kennedy%EF%BC%9APresidential%20Inaugural%20Address/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/John%20F.%20Kennedy%EF%BC%9APresidential%20Inaugural%20Address/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T15:15:19.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T09:36:45.944Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=753262888&bvid=BV1zk4y167L2&cid=197165599&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>Vice President Johnson, Mr. Speaker, Mr. Chief Justice, President Eisenhower, Vice President Nixon, President Truman, reverend clergy, fellow citizens:</p><p>We observe today not a victory of party, but a celebration of freedom – symbolizing an end,as well as a beginning – signifying renewal, as well as change. For I have sworn before you and Almighty God the same solemn oath our forebears prescribed nearly a century and threequarters ago.</p><p>The world is very different now. For man holds in his mortal hands the power to abolish all forms of human poverty and all forms of human life. And yet the same revolutionary beliefs for which our forebears fought are still at issue around the globe – the belief that the rights of man come not from the generosity of the state, but from the hand of God.</p><p>We dare not forget today that we are the heirs of that first revolution. Let the word go forth from this time and place, to friend and foe alike, that the torch has been passed to a new generation of Americans – born in this century, tempered by war, disciplined by a hard and bitter peace, proud of our ancient heritage, and unwilling to witness or permit the slow undoing of those human rights to which this nation has always been committed, and to which we are committed today at home and around the world.  </p><p>Let every nation know, whether it wishes us well or ill, that we shall pay any price, bear any burden, meet any hardship, support any friend, oppose any foe, to assure the survival and the success of liberty.</p><p>This much we pledge – and more.</p><p>To those old allies whose cultural and spiritual origins we share, we pledge the loyalty of faithful friends. United there is little we cannot do in a host of cooperative ventures. Divided there is little we can do – for we dare not meet a powerful challenge at odds and split asunder.</p><p>To those new states whom we welcome to the ranks of the free, we pledge our word that one form of colonial control shall not have passed away merely to be replaced by a far more iron tyranny. We shall not always expect to find them supporting our view. But we shall always hope to find them strongly supporting their own freedom – and to remember that, in the past, those who foolishly sought power by riding the back of the tiger ended up inside. To those people in the huts and villages of half the globe struggling to break the bonds of mass misery, we pledge our best efforts to help them help themselves, for whatever period is required – not because the Communists may be doing it, not because we seek their votes,but because it is right. If a free society cannot help the many who are poor, it cannot save the few who are rich.</p><p>To our sister republics south of our border, we offer a special pledge: to convert our good words into good deeds, in a new alliance for progress, to assist free men and free governments in casting off the chains of poverty. But this peaceful revolution of hope cannot become the prey of hostile powers. Let all our neighbors know that we shall join with them to oppose aggression or subversion anywhere in the Americas. And let every other power know that this hemisphere intends to remain the master of its own house.</p><p>To that world assembly of sovereign states, the United Nations, our last best hope in an age where the instruments of war have far outpaced the instruments of peace, we renew our pledge of support – to prevent it from becoming merely a forum for invective, to strengthen its shield of the new and the weak, and to enlarge the area in which its writ may run.</p><p>Finally, to those nations who would make themselves our adversary, we offer not a pledge but a request: that both sides begin anew the quest for peace, before the dark powers of destruction unleashed by science engulf all humanity in planned or accidental self-destruction.</p><p>We dare not tempt them with weakness. For only when our arms are sufficient beyond doubt can we be certain beyond doubt that they will never be employed.  </p><p>But neither can two great and powerful groups of nations take comfort from our present course – both sides overburdened by the cost of modern weapons, both rightly alarmed by the steady spread of the deadly atom, yet both racing to alter that uncertain balance of terror that stays the hand of mankind’s final war.</p><p>So let us begin anew – remembering on both sides that civility is not a sign of weakness, and sincerity is always subject to proof. Let us never negotiate out of fear, but let us never fear to negotiate.</p><p>Let both sides explore what problems unite us instead of belaboring those problems which divide us.</p><p>Let both sides, for the first time, formulate serious and precise proposals for the inspection and control of arms, and bring the absolute power to destroy other nations under the absolute control of all nations.</p><p>Let both sides seek to invoke the wonders of science instead of its terrors. Together let us explore the stars, conquer the deserts, eradicate disease, tap the ocean depths, and encourage the arts and commerce.</p><p>Let both sides unite to heed, in all corners of the earth, the command of Isaiah – to “undo the heavy burdens, and [to] let the oppressed go free.”</p><p>And, if a beachhead of cooperation may push back the jungle of suspicion, let both sides join in creating a new endeavor – not a new balance of power, but a new world of law – where the strong are just, and the weak secure, and the peace preserved.</p><p>All this will not be finished in the first one hundred days. Nor will it be finished in the first one thousand days; nor in the life of this Administration; nor even perhaps in our lifetime on this planet. But let us begin.</p><p>In your hands, my fellow citizens, more than mine, will rest the final success or failure of our course. Since this country was founded, each generation of Americans has been summoned to give testimony to its national loyalty. The graves of young Americans who answered the call to service surround the globe.</p><p>Now the trumpet summons us again – not as a call to bear arms, though arms we need – not as a call to battle, though embattled we are – but a call to bear the burden of a long twilight struggle, year in and year out, “rejoicing in hope; patient in tribulation,” a struggle against the common enemies of man: tyranny, poverty, disease, and war itself.</p><p>Can we forge against these enemies a grand and global alliance, North and South, East and West, that can assure a more fruitful life for all mankind? Will you join in that historic effort?</p><p>In the long history of the world, only a few generations have been granted the role of defending freedom in its hour of maximum danger. I do not shrink from this responsibility – I welcome it. I do not believe that any of us would exchange places with any other people or any other generation. The energy, the faith, the devotion which we bring to this endeavor will light our country and all who serve it. And the glow from that fire can truly light the world. </p><p>And so, my fellow Americans, ask not what your country can do for you; ask what you can do for your country.</p><p>My fellow citizens of the world, ask not what America will do for you, but what together we can do for the freedom of man.</p><p>Finally,whether you are citizens of America or citizens of the world, ask of us here the same high standards of strength and sacrifice which we ask of you. With a good conscience our only sure reward, with history the final judge of our deeds, let us go forth to lead the land we love,asking His blessing and His help, but knowing that here on earth God’s work must truly be our own.</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=753262888&amp;bvid=BV1zk4y167L2&amp;cid=197165599&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>千日紀事</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/%E5%8D%83%E6%97%A5%E7%B4%80%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/30/%E5%8D%83%E6%97%A5%E7%B4%80%E4%BA%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-30T09:45:52.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-02T05:24:22.712Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/aZdrF6ePhMGyv3Y.jpg" alt="img"></p><a id="more"></a><p>庚子年閏四月初八日。</p><p>晴空萬里</p><p>自2017-09-03到2020-05-30，已然走入大學達千日。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.loli.net/2020/05/31/aZdrF6ePhMGyv3Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="庚子紀實" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E7%B4%80%E5%AF%A6/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>George W. Bush：911 Address to the Nation</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/George%20W.%20Bush%EF%BC%9A911%20Address%20to%20the%20Nation/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/George%20W.%20Bush%EF%BC%9A911%20Address%20to%20the%20Nation/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:50:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-03T14:40:36.698Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=838262311&bvid=BV1vg4y1B7bn&cid=198320136&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>Good evening.</p><p>Today, our fellow citizens, our way of life, our very freedom came under attack in a series of deliberate and deadly terrorist acts. The victims were in airplanes or in their offices: secretaries, business men and women, military and federal workers, moms and dads, friends and neighbors. Thousands of lives were suddenly ended by evil, despicable acts of terror. The pictures of airplanes flying into buildings, fires burning, huge ­­ huge structures collapsing have filled us with disbelief, terrible sadness, and a quiet, unyielding anger. These acts of mass murder were intended to frighten our nation into chaos and retreat. But they have failed. Our country is strong.</p><p>A great people has been moved to defend a great nation. Terrorist attacks can shake the foundations of our biggest buildings, but they cannot touch the foundation of America. These acts shatter steel, but they cannot dent the steel of American resolve. America was targeted for attack because we’re the brightest beacon for freedom and opportunity in the world. And no one will keep that light from shining. Today, our nation saw evil ­­ the very worst of human nature ­­ and we responded with the best of America. With the daring of our rescue workers,with the caring for strangers and neighbors who came to give blood and help in any way they could.</p><p>Immediately following the first attack, I implemented our government’s emergency response plans. Our military is powerful, and it’s prepared. Our emergency teams are working in New York City and Washington D.C. to help with local rescue efforts. Our first priority is to get help to those who have been injured, and to take every precaution to protect our citizens at home and around the world from further attacks. The functions of our government continue without interruption. Federal agencies in Washington which had to be evacuated today are reopening for essential personnel tonight and will be open for business tomorrow. Our financial institutions remain strong, and the American economy will be open for business as well.</p><p>The search is underway for those who were behind these evil acts. I have directed the full resources of our intelligence and law enforcement communities to find those responsible andto bring them to justice. We will make no distinction between the terrorists who committedthese acts and those who harbor them.</p><p>Iappreciate so very much the members of Congress who have joined me in strongly condemning these attacks. And on behalf of the American people, I thank the many world leaders who have called to offer their condolences and assistance. America and our friendsand allies join with all those who want peace and security in the world, and we stand togetherto win the war against terrorism.</p><p>Tonight, I ask for your prayers for all those who grieve, for the children whose worlds have been shattered, for all whose sense of safety and security has been threatened. And I pray they will be comforted by a Power greater than any of us, spoken through the ages in Psalm23: Even though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death, I fear no evil for you are with me.</p><p>This is a day when all Americans from every walk of life unite in our resolve for justice and peace. America has stood down enemies before, and we will do so this time. None of us will ever forget this day, yet we go forward to defend freedom and all that is good and just in our world.</p><p>Thank you. Good night. And God bless America.  </p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=838262311&amp;bvid=BV1vg4y1B7bn&amp;cid=198320136&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>A Beautiful Mind - The Nobel Prize</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/A%20Beautiful%20Mind%20-%20The%20Nobel%20Prize/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/A%20Beautiful%20Mind%20-%20The%20Nobel%20Prize/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:48:48.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:39.191Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=840782239&bvid=BV1q54y1D7qq&cid=196323697&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=840782239&amp;bvid=BV1q54y1D7qq&amp;cid=196323697&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dilios&#39; Battle Call at Plataea</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Dilios&#39;%20Battle%20Call%20at%20Plataea/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Dilios&#39;%20Battle%20Call%20at%20Plataea/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T14:46:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:18:21.839Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=243340752&bvid=BV1kv411z7aD&cid=196323093&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=243340752&amp;bvid=BV1kv411z7aD&amp;cid=196323093&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>【梅豔芳】似是故人來</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%A2%85%E8%B1%94%E8%8A%B3%E3%80%91%E4%BC%BC%E6%98%AF%E6%95%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%BE%86/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%A2%85%E8%B1%94%E8%8A%B3%E3%80%91%E4%BC%BC%E6%98%AF%E6%95%85%E4%BA%BA%E4%BE%86/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T03:10:21.446Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-31T16:15:24.921Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=285790377&bvid=BV1Pf4y127GQ&cid=196286766&page=1&high_quality=1"  scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true" sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><p>深夜配老歌，明月在天。</p><a id="more"></a><p>昨日同可愛夜聊。聊到了許多老歌，如此夜晚，老歌更讓人回味。粵語保留了許多中古漢語的音調，聲調豐富，吟唱中文最合適不過。</p><p>初聽《似是故人來》，是洪塵的翻唱版，洪塵嗓音乾淨環味。若是要為自己那段時間做一首音樂註腳，莫過於這首《似是故人來》。林夕作詞，頗有長短句之韻。“恨臺上卿卿，或臺下我我，不是我跟你” 和 “斷腸字點點，風雨聲連連，似是故人來”，最是讓人絞腸。</p><iframe frameborder="no" border="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" width=530 height=86 src="//music.163.com/outchain/player?type=2&id=543747557&auto=0&height=66"></iframe><hr><center>作詞：林夕  作曲：羅大佑</center><center>同是過路，同做過夢</center><center>本應是一對</center><center>人在少年，夢中不覺</center><center>醒後要歸去</center><center>三餐一宿，也共一雙</center><center>到底會是誰</center><center>但凡未得到</center><center>但凡是過去</center><center>總是最登對</center><center>臺下你望，臺上我做</center><center>你想做的戲</center><center>前世故人，忘憂的你</center><center>可曾記得起</center><center>歡喜傷悲，老病生死</center><center>說不上傳奇</center><center>恨臺上卿卿</center><center>或臺下我我</center><center>不是我跟你</center><center>俗塵渺渺</center><center>天意茫茫</center><center>將你共我分開</center><center>斷腸字點點</center><center>風雨聲連連</center><center>似是故人來</center><center>何日再追，何地再醉</center><center>說今夜真美</center><center>無份有緣，回憶不斷</center><center>生命卻苦短</center><center>一種相思，兩段苦戀 </center><center>半生說沒完</center><center>在年月深淵</center><center>望明月遠遠</center><center>想像你憂鬱</center><center>俗塵渺渺</center><center>天意茫茫</center><center>將你共我分開</center><center>斷腸字點點</center><center>風雨聲連連</center><center>似是故人來</center><center>留下你或留下我</center><center>在世間上終老</center><center>離別以前</center><center>未知相對當日那麼好</center><center>執子之手</center><center>卻又分手</center><center>愛得有還無</center><center>十年後雙雙</center><center>萬年後對對</center><center>只恨看不到</center><center>十年後雙雙</center><center>萬年後對對</center><center>只恨看不到</center>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=285790377&amp;bvid=BV1Pf4y127GQ&amp;cid=196286766&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot;  scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;深夜配老歌，明月在天。&lt;/p&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Queen Gorgo Address the Spartan Apella</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Queen%20Gorgo%20Address%20the%20Spartan%20Apella/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/Queen%20Gorgo%20Address%20the%20Spartan%20Apella/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T01:59:32.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-05-29T15:17:10.770Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=837832074&bvid=BV1Pg4y1z7HL&cid=196258724&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true"sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe><a id="more"></a><p>希波戰爭期間，波斯國王薛西斯一世親率30萬大軍征戰希臘，希臘防線最前線便是溫泉關，此處亦是波斯前往希臘的必經之路。叛徒出賣之後，斯巴達國王列奧尼達為保留希臘聯軍實力，讓聯軍先撤退，而自己率三百斯巴達勇士死守溫泉關。</p><p>視頻中，他的女人——斯巴達王后戈爾戈在兩軍交戰明顯己方處於劣勢的背景下，憑藉三寸之舌，以一國王后的傲然氣勢，說服議會出兵抗擊波斯，解救斯巴達勇士。</p><p>有件軼事能一窺戈爾戈的氣魄。有次戈爾戈訪問雅典，一個女人問她，為何斯巴達女人能控制住自己的男人。戈爾戈回答，因為只有斯巴達女人能生男人。</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=837832074&amp;bvid=BV1Pg4y1z7HL&amp;cid=196258724&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; framespacing=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;sandbox=&quot;allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="Speeches" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/Speeches/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>【浮生一紀】悲喜交加的故事</title>
    <link href="http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%B5%AE%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%80%E7%B4%80%E3%80%91%E6%82%B2%E5%96%9C%E4%BA%A4%E5%8A%A0%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B/"/>
    <id>http://nichtsein.github.io/2020/05/29/%E3%80%90%E6%B5%AE%E7%94%9F%E4%B8%80%E7%B4%80%E3%80%91%E6%82%B2%E5%96%9C%E4%BA%A4%E5%8A%A0%E7%9A%84%E6%95%85%E4%BA%8B/</id>
    <published>2020-05-29T01:00:58.000Z</published>
    <updated>2020-06-02T05:24:06.257Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<iframe src="//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710873160&bvid=BV1vQ4y1P7ni&cid=196205833&page=1&high_quality=1" scrolling="no" border="0" frameborder="no" framespacing="0" allowfullscreen="true"sandbox="allow-top-navigation allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"> </iframe>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;iframe src=&quot;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?aid=710873160&amp;bvid=BV1vQ4y1P7ni&amp;cid=196205833&amp;page=1&amp;high_quality=1&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; border=&quot;0
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="庚子紀實" scheme="http://nichtsein.github.io/categories/%E5%BA%9A%E5%AD%90%E7%B4%80%E5%AF%A6/"/>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
